《洛奇6： 永远的拳王》
对梅森·迪克逊而言这又是一次迅速的
Yet another quick knockout for Mason Dixon,
击倒性胜利 马马虎虎的一场比赛
almost perfunctory.
拳击迷们的反应让他知道  他们不是那么满意
The fans let him know how they feel about it.
把女人和小孩藏起来吧 场面可能会变得混乱
Hide the women and children. This could get ugly.
这群粉丝完全没有掩饰对这场比赛的不满
This crowd does nothing to hide its anger over this latest debacle.
粉丝们都火到不行了 他们不想再经历这样乏味的比赛了
The fans are mad as hell. They don't want to take it anymore.
他们好像在怪优秀的拳击手迪克逊
They seem to be blaming Dixon,
因为这种选手走下坡的现象
a good fighter, for the decline...
不只是重量级拳击 而是整个拳击界
...not only of the heavyweight-division guys, but of the entire sport.
他们甚至向不败的世界拳王
They're actually pelting...
扔冰块
...the undefeated heavyweight champion of the world with ice.
或许这种打从心底的愤怒会促使 拳王迪克逊找一个
Maybe this angry, visceral reaction will pressure Dixon to fight someone...
与自己实力相近的选手 以此换来 新的竞技气氛
...who can fight back for a change. If there's somebody out there.
整个拳击运动都期盼着一位 能用他的激情震撼观众心灵的选手
All of boxing is hoping for a warrior who thrills us with his passion.
时间过得太快了
Time goes by too fast.
是吗 我觉得还不够快
Yeah? Not fast enough.
- 你的孩子应该来的 - 没关系的
- Your kid should've been here. - That's all right.
- 不 有关系 - 孩子有时候有点忙
- No, it ain't all right. - The kid gets a little busy sometimes.
也不会忙成那个样子吧
He don't get that busy.
我们别在这谈了 好吗 你今晚会来吧 是吗
Let's not talk about it here, okay? You're coming tonight, right?
我在工作 过去三年我一直在巡历
I'm working. I took the tour the last three years.
我知道 但今晚是周年纪念啊
I know, but it's the anniversary.
好的 我答应你
Fine. You got my word.
我很感激你的承诺 谢谢你 算我欠你一次 保利
I appreciate it, thank you. I owe you, Paulie.
罗伯特 怎么回事 你去哪了 你迟到了
Yo, Robert. What's going on? Where have you been? You're late.
不 我不想真的知道你去哪了 听着 你的工作表现
No. I don't wanna hear this. Look, your job performance...
不足以掩盖你迟到这个事实
...is nowhere near good enough to be pulling this.
我不在乎你老爸是谁 明白吗
I don't give a damn who your father is. You understand me?
- 懂了的话现在就去工作 - 好的
- All right. Now get out of here. - Okay.
先生 谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
罗伯特
Yo, Robert. Yo.
- 你好 洛奇 - 你好
- Hey, Rocky. - Hey.
- 最近好吗 - 你好
- Hey, how you doing? - Hey.
你好吗 冠军
What's up, champ?
- 你在我没准备的时候找我 - 我知道
- You caught me off guard. - I know.
我想在你变得太忙之前找你
I wanted to catch you before you got busy.
是的 楼上还有很多事要做
Yeah, it gets busy up there.
- 最近好吗 - 真的很好
- So how you doing? Yeah? - Real good. Yeah.
- 洛奇 - 你好
- Yo, Rock! - Yeah, how you doing?
是的 真的很好
Yeah, real good.
听着 你想出去喝杯咖啡吗
Listen, you wanna go out and get some coffee?
我要迟到了 或许以后吧
I'm kind of behind. Maybe later?
好的 那也行 你今晚要来餐厅一下
Yeah. That'd be great. You ought to come by the restaurant tonight.
我可以帮你煮点好吃的
I can have something made special for you.
今晚不行 我有计划了 一群朋友聚在一起
Tonight I can't. I got plans. A few of the guys get together.
- 我是不是做错什么了 - 你的意思是?
- Did I do something wrong? - What do you mean?
我也不知道是什么意思...
Well, I don't know exactly what I mean...
但我在想 我来到这里的时候 你总是不自在
...but I just think, like, when I come here, you don't feel so comfortable.
当然 我不想让你不自在
And I certainly don't wanna do that.
- 你给我一个很大的阴影 - 一个很大的阴影？
- Well, you throw a big shadow. - A big shadow?
你在这里什么都做不了 罗伯特
You're not gonna get anything done down here, Robert.
好吧 你不打算介绍我的话 我自己来
Well, if you're not gonna introduce me,
你好 我是 威廉·汤姆逊
I will. Hi, I'm William Tomilson.
- 你好 - 你儿子很不幸为我工作
- How you doing? - Your son works for me.
- 这是一份好工作 - 是的
- It's a good job. - Yeah.
你知道吗 我已经对罗伯特说过二十次要见你了
I've told Robert about 20 times that I wanted to meet you.
你真的很忙 这是件好事 是吗
You're pretty busy, which isn't a bad thing.
- 有些事情阻碍着 - 帮我们拍张照片吧 好吗
- I get a little tied up. - Grab a shot, will you?
我可能再也没有这样的机会了 老战友们总是团结在一起的
I may not get this chance again. Old warhorses have to stick together.
- 老战友们 是的 - 走着瞧吧
- The old horses, yeah. - I'll tell you.
- 还好这不是你的左手 - 这个姿势让你受欢迎
- Good thing it's not your left. - This makes you popular with people.
- 一 二 三 - 见到你太好了
- One, two, three. - Finally, we get to meet.
我要干活了 能当面见你真的太好了
I gotta get going. It was nice to meet you face to face.
你好好照顾自己 罗伯特 我们晚些再见
You take care of yourself. Robert, I'll see you later.
我要走了 我会改变今晚的计划
I gotta get going. I'll change my plans for tonight.
那样就好 我很期待今晚见到你
That'd be great. I'm looking forward to it.
- 最近好吧 - 还好
- How you doing? - Okay.
- 好的 - 好
- Okay. - All right.
别让那些数字烦到你
And do not let those numbers drive you crazy.
- 太晚啦 - 用橡皮擦把那些数字都抹掉
- Too late. - Use an eraser, get rid of all of them.
- 洛奇 - 伙计们
- Yo, Rock. - Hey, guys.
- 洛奇 - 你最近好吗
- Hey, Rock. - Hey, how you doing?
好了 你的
There you go.
我要10个10号的 你们要照顾好自己
It'll be about 10 tenths. You guys take care, okay? You got it.
稍后我会买这些试试
I'll try a few of these later on.
- 这些烤起来很香 - 多少钱?
- It's good for baking. - How much?
- 保罗 这个多少钱 - 58.40美金 先生
- Yo, Paul, what's the cost? - 58.40, sir.
好的 从这里面扣吧 我相信你
All right, take it out of that. I trust you.
- 最近好吗 - 你太大方了
- How you doing? - You're too generous.
没问题的
Not a problem.
你们都好吗
How you guys doing?
生意还好吧 伊莎贝尔
How we doing, Isabel?
还可以 除了那正看圣经不给钱的家伙
Okay, except for the freebie reading the Bible.
- 没关系的 - 就因为你以前和他交过手
- He's okay. - Just because you fought him...
不代表你要养他一辈子 他现在都不像一个拳击手了
...don't mean you gotta feed him. He doesn't look like a fighter.
斯拜德·瑞高 还能当拳击手
Spider Rico could hit.
- 听着 你的肚子还好吗 - 还行
- Listen, how's your stomach? - It's okay.
如果你不断地往你肚子上抹橄榄油
If you keep rubbing olive oil on your stomach...
你生的孩子会很强壮
...your kid's gonna be born very strong.
- 好的 洛奇 随便你怎么说 - 不 我是认真的
- Okay, Rocky. Whatever you say. - No, really.
- 你还好吗 斯拜德 - 上帝保佑你 洛奇
- Yo, how you doing, Spider? - God bless you, Rocky.
谢谢你
Thanks.
你们都好吧
How you guys doing?
宙斯 你能帮今晚我来的儿子弄些特别的菜吗
Jose, can you make something special for my kid who's coming tonight?
没问题
No problemo.
好的 感激不尽
Good. I appreciate it.
我在场上走来走去 走来走去 然后互让
Back and forth, back and forth, give and take.
然后我像猛兽一样向前冲把他摔到场角
And then I went in there like an animal and threw him into the corner...
我把我全身的力量都使出来了
...and I unloaded everything I had.
钩拳 钩拳 钩拳 往左往左往左
Hook, hook, hook, left, left, left.
然而克瑞特 他拚命地回击
But Creed, he kept busting me back pretty good...
一股巨大疼痛感涌上心头
...and the agony began to pile up.
然后我听到了这一辈子 最动听的铃声
Then I heard the best sound that I ever heard in my life...
- 比赛结束的铃声 - 是的
- The bell. - That's right, the bell.
我从来都没那么累过 我坐在场角
I ain't never been so tired, and I'm sitting in my corner.
我在尝试思考怎样坚持打完最后一轮
I'm trying to figure out how to survive the last round...
当米奇靠过来 对着我的耳朵说
...when Mickey leans into my ear and says:
加油 冲出去打那家伙一顿 你这废物
"Come on, get out there and fight this guy hard, you bum.
你一定要拿第一 一定 我说 如果我能的话
You gotta be first. You gotta be first." I said, "Yo, Mick, if I could...
- 我会的 - 我会的
- "I would." - ...I would."
故事讲完了
The end.
对梅森·迪克逊而言这又是一次迅速的
Yet another quick knockout for Mason Dixon,
击倒性胜利 马马虎虎的一场比赛
almost perfunctory.
拳击迷们的反应让他知道 他们不是那么满意
The fans let him know how they feel about it.
他们甚至向不败的
They're actually pelting...
世界拳王冷言冷语
...the undefeated heavyweight champion of the world with ice.
你好 阿吉瑞安餐厅 是吗
Hello, Adrian's. Yeah?
要我告诉他你不能来了 好的 我会告诉他的
Tell him you can't make it? Yeah, I'll give him the message.
在我脑子里不断回荡着米奇的声音
I just kept hearing Mickey's voice in my head over and over again.
我匍匐着身体 在此之前
I just dug down, and before you know it...
当时靠得很近 稍等
...it was toe to toe and it was... Excuse me.
你的儿子说他今晚不能来了 他说他要延期 好吗
Your son said he can't make it. He said he'll take a rain check. Okay?
看看这些鸟
Look at these birds.
它们象不象糖果 会飞的糖果
Don't these birds look like candy? Flying candy?
小鸟 你想飞回家吗
Hey, birdie, you wanna fly me home?
你要人陪你回家吗
You need somebody to walk you home?
不需要吗
No?
晚上很冷 在生活里我们需要些欢笑声
It's a cold night. We need a few laughs in our life.
你觉得呢 也许吗
What do you think? Maybe?
也许 也许？
Maybe? Maybe?
好吧 让我们离开这里吧 好吗
Okay. Let's get out of here, okay?
那地方从去年起就没怎么改变
That place ain't changed much from last year.
看够了吗
Are we done?
米克 最近好吗
Hey, how you doing, Mick?
那个牌匾正裂开 保利
That sign is falling apart, Paulie.
整个世界都在分裂 瞧瞧我们
The whole world is falling apart. Look at us.
别乱说话 保利
Don't talk crazy, Paulie.
你知道吗 如果你在某一个地方待久了
You know, I think if you live someplace long enough,
你也会成为那个地方的一部分
you are that place.
我又不是在讲那些大楼
I ain't no talking building.
快走吧 天开始晚了 小洛
Come on, it's getting late, Rocko.
那火车声弄到我头痛
I get a headache from this train.
我记得她站在那里的模样
I remember when she was standing there...
很紧张 也很害羞 带着淡淡的笑容
...all nervous and shy, with this little smile.
我最想让她做的事是信任我
And all I wanted her to do was trust me.
她做到了
She did.
- 她做到了 - 你好了吗
- She did. - You done?
- 我们还要在这里待多久 - 不会太久的
- How long are we staying here? - Not long.
他们把这溜冰场给拆了 我真高兴
Well, I'm glad they tore this ice rink down.
拜托
Come on.
你听到了吗 他们把溜冰场拆了 我很高兴
You heard me. I'm happy they tore it apart.
第一次陪你妹妹滑这溜冰场的时候 当时我们在那边
First time I walked your sister across this ice, we was over there.
她很紧张 我当时也不知道怎么溜冰
She was nervous, but I wasn't so great on the blades either.
冰最无聊 站在冰块上的人更无聊
Ice is stupid. People standing on ice are more stupid.
她就摔倒在那边
And over there, when she was falling...
我手扶着她
...and my hand grabbed her...
我从她的大衣中挽住她的手臂 我能感到
...and I got her arm through that coat, I could feel it.
一股电流
Electric.
你和去年说的一样 小洛
You said the same thing last year, Rock.
是吗
Did I?
你最好让你的脑子发育一下
So you better develop your brain.
- 你是左撇子 - 是的
- You're left-handed. - Absolutely.
来吧 小洛 咱们走
Come on, Rock. Let's go.
我们看完了 这地方没地方坐
We're done. There's no place to sit down around here.
没关系的
It's all right.
有关系 这儿让人沮丧 而且冷得要命
It ain't all right! It's depressing and freaking cold!
你是怎么了 保利
What's the matter with you, Paulie?
你活在过去 小洛
You're living backwards, Rocko!
把生活的调子调回现在吧 过去也不是太美好
Change the channel from yesterday! Yesterday wasn't so great!
- 这是对我而言的 - 不是对我而言
- It was to me. - Not to me!
你对她那么好 你们过了段好日子
You treated her good. You had the good times.
我对她那么差 我不需要回想过去的生活
I treated her bad. I don't have to think about this.
她永远爱你 保利
She always loved you, Paulie.
对不起 小洛 我不能再干这些事了
Sorry, Rocko, I can't do this no more.
你需要点什么
Can I help you?
不不 我过去常常来这个地方坐
No, no, I used to come down to this place a long time ago.
我只是坐坐 问题不大
I was just looking around. No big deal.
你要点喝的吗
Can I get you a drink?
- 好的 那来点酒吧 - 马上来
- All right. Maybe just a short beer. - Okay.
去 快去
Go. Go on.
是啊 去 叫他付我们的下一轮的酒钱
Yeah, go on. Get him to buy a round.
让他付我们的下一轮的酒钱
Get him to buy a round. Go.
让他付 他有钱 他在花钱
Get him to... He's got it. He's spending money.
听着 我不是想了解你的私事
Listen, I don't mean to cross the line or anything...
但我听到些关于你妻子去世的事
...but I read about your wife's passing a few years back.
是的 是女人才有的癌症
Yeah, it was woman cancer.
是的 我常常听到人说她是个好人
Yeah. I always heard she was a nice person.
是的 最好的人
Yeah, the best.
- 我认识你吗 - 我们在很久之前见过面
- Do I know you? - We met a long time ago.
真的吗
We did?
当我还是小孩子的时候 你送我回家
When I was a kid, you walked me home.
- 我送你回家吗 - 叫我别再抽烟之类的
- I did? - Told me to stop smoking and things.
别抽烟
Stop smoking...
你是当年那个经常去阿唐米克的小玛丽吗
Are you Little Marie that used to hang out at that Atomic Hoagie shop?
是的 说对了
Yeah, that's right.
太好了 我记起来了 我送过你回家
Yeah, now I remember. I walked you home.
走到家门口的时候 你转过头来 对我说 去死吧 讨厌鬼
When you got there, you turned around and said, "Screw you, creepo."
- 我没那样说吧 - 有 你有这样说
- I didn't say that. - Yeah, you did.
- 你确定吗 - 特大侮辱会让人难忘的
- You sure? - Great insults last a long time.
是你吗 真的是你吗
Yo! Yo, is that you? Is that really you?
- 你最近好吗 - 我觉得他想一个人喝酒
- How you doing? - I think he wants to drink alone.
好啊 那么给他想喝的 我又没有阻止你
Well, then give him his drink, then. I ain't stopping you.
你是怎么了 他是你的男人吗 不 不是 我不那么认为
What's that, your man or something? No, I don't think so.
总之 我和我的伙计们 刚好在这喝酒
Anyway, me and my friends, we're right down there.
我想你可以买我们下一轮 要喝的酒 就一轮酒
Think you could buy us a round? You got the money. Just one round.
谢谢
Hey. Thank you.
你在干什么 把我的手用力推开
What are you doing pushing my hand away like that?
- 你的名字是什么 - 安吉 你知道我的名字有什么用
- What's your name? - Angie. What do you wanna know for?
- 别像个傻子跟着那个人 - 一傻子？
- Don't be playing a fool for that guy. - A fool?
- 是的 - 一个傻子？
- Yeah. - A fool?
我是傻子？ 你才是傻子 我才不是
I'm the fool? You're the fool, not me!
你误会了 你是傻子 我是一正常人 就和你一样
You got it twisted. You're the fool. I'm a person, just like you.
你比我好不了多少
You aren't no better than me.
你现在是一贵客又如何 你什么都不是
You think you're a big shot now? You're nothing.
你比我好不了多少 好不了多少
You ain't no better than me. No better!
欢迎来我们这里
Glad you dropped in?
我想这周围变了很多
I think the neighborhood is changing a little.
- 刚发生了什么 - 我也不知道 忘了它吧
- What was that all about? - I don't know. Forget about it.
我快要关门了 你想下班 我去点账吧
I'm gonna lock up, so if you wanna take off, I'll tally everything up.
- 好的 谢谢 - 最近好吗 小洛
- Yeah, thanks. - How you doing, Rock?
我很好 谢谢
I'm good, thanks.
- 你住在这里吗 - 离这里有八个街区远的地方
- You live around here? - About eight blocks from here.
八个街区
Eight blocks.
你想搭顺风车吗
You need a lift?
好啊
All right.
你结过婚吗
Did you ever get married?
- 有吧 - 有吧？
- Yeah, sort of. - Sort of?
- 是的 怎么说呢 他离开我了 - 那样就告吹了
- Yeah, well, he took off. - Poof, just like that?
是的 那样就结束了
Yeah, just like that.
- 你有孩子的吧 - 是的 我有
- You sort of have any kids? - Yeah, I got one kid.
是吗 我也是 我也是 是个很棒的男孩儿
Yeah? Me too. Me too. Wonderful boy.
牛人 你是怎么了 不可以帮我们买一轮酒喝喝
Hey, tough guy! What's the matter, you can't buy a round?
那女孩子刚刚对你这种蠢货那么好
The girl was being nice to your dumb ass.
你拿什么给予我们回报呢 蠢猪
What you doing with that pig?
你觉得这样就可以侮辱我们了吗
Think you can disrespect us?
- 她只是个会嫉妒的婊子 - 来啊 过来啊
- She ain't nothing but a jealous bitch! -  Come on back!
算了 别听他们的
Hey, don't listen to them.
你们两个都比我好不了多少
Both of youse, you ain't no better than me.
过来啊 你的头会被我踢破的
Come over here, you'll get your head kicked in around here.
- 你这个酒鬼 笨杂种 - 你又不是什么贵客 瞧瞧你自己
- You punch-drunk, goofy bastard. - You ain't no big shot, look at you.
你连送那头猪回去的车都没有
You ain't even got a car to take that pig home.
你还好吗
You all right?
还好
Yeah.
你想干吗 别出去 没关系的
What are you doing? Don't get out. It's all right.
不 小玛丽 有关系
No, Little Marie. It ain't all right.
- 呦 - 你问怎么了
- Yo. - What?
让我告诉你 进去
I'll tell you what. Get inside.
- 进去 你进去 - 放开他
- You get inside. Yeah, you. - Hey, leave him alone!
- 伙计 - 看到了吗
- Yo, man! - See it?
- 看那里 看那里 - 是的 是的
- You see that? You see that? - Yeah. All right.
- 你想说些什么 - 对不起 对不起
- What do you say? - I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
去找份工作
Get a job!
那个人道歉了
That guy sends his apologies.
好的
Okay.
马丁 马丁
Martin. Martin. Yo, Martin!
你还有钥匙
I see you still got your key.
是的 我有 你有时间谈谈吗
Yeah, I got a key. You got time to talk?
自从你们炒了我以后 我有很多时间
I got a lot of time since your people let me go.
你知道你被开除与我无关
You know I had nothing to do with that.
是的
Yeah.
我们一年前搬到这里
Yeah, we moved in about a year ago.
- 真的吗 - 是的 我们只是暂时住在这里
- Yeah? - Yeah, I mean, it's only temporary.
- 是的 我看得出来 - 我之后会看看住宅楼
- Yeah, I could see that. - I'm gonna look for an apartment.
住宅楼都很不错
Apartments are nice.
是的 房子就是那样
Yeah. It is what it is, you know.
房子就是那样
Yeah, it is what it is.
以前这个地方很不错 这里可算历史悠久
This place used to be pretty nice. There's a lot of history around here.
- 是吗 - 譬如这条街的尽头
- Yeah. - Like down the street...
是一家叫哥伦比亚的搏击会
...is the Cambria Fight Club.
过去人们叫它一桶血
They used to call it the Bucket of Blood.
在那里我打过几次硬仗 无论如何 那里都有美好的回忆
I took some massive beatings there. But it was nice. Good memories.
我听说过 这些建筑物有一百年或 一百五十年历史了
And I heard these buildings are like, I don't know, 100, 150 years old.
如果我也有一百五十岁 我会支离破碎的 但对建筑而言无所谓
If I was 150 years old, I'd be falling apart too. So it's okay, building.
那是灯留下来的吗
Does that light work?
- 不 那是被烧毁的痕迹或其他弄的 - 是吗
- No, it's burnt out or something. Yeah. - Yeah?
听着 我很感谢你送我回来 那些小子打扰到你的话 抱歉了
Listen, thanks for the ride, and I'm sorry about those guys.
一些小伙子总是不动脑筋
Some of those guys just got their brains on backwards and stuff.
- 他这么晚了 还在外面干什么 - 那是你的孩子吗
- What's he doing out so late? - Is that your kid?
是的 希望他别在外面待太久
Yeah. Wish he wouldn't stay out so late.
- 真是惊人 - 是吗 为什么
- Amazing. - Yeah, what's that?
上次遇见你的时候 你只是一个黄毛丫头
Last time I seen you, you was a kid...
而现在你有自己的孩子了
...and now you officially got one of your own.
真的很棒
It's amazing.
你知道吗 他和你有点像 他也有爱尔兰人的发色
You know, he sort of resembles you. He's got that big Irish hair.
是的 其实是另外一个孩子
Yeah, it's the other one.
- 是吗 - 他父亲是牙买加人
- Yeah? - His father was from Jamaica.
牙买加人 欧洲人
Jamaica? European.
你认识你丈夫的时候在坐油轮吗
Was you on a cruise ship or something?
- 不 不是那样的 - 他的名字是?
- No, not really. - What's his name?
- 小史 是史帝芬的缩写 - 有道理
- Steps. Short for Stevenson. - Makes sense.
他对着我生气吗 还是我站的角度 看上去他在生气
Does he look mad at me, or is it maybe the angle I'm standing at?
不 他是个好孩子
No. He's a good kid.
- 你想见见他吗 - 现在有点晚了
- You wanna meet him? - It's getting kind of late.
- 我有很多东西要忙 - 是 我了解
- I got so many things to do. - Yeah, yeah, I understand.
再次谢谢你把我送回来 你给的一切
Thanks again for the ride and everything else.
再见
I'll see you.
You too.
小史 过来 对你的朋友说声晚安
Hey, Steps, come on. Let's go. Say good night to your friend.
这么冷的天 你在外面又不戴帽子 干了些什么
What are you doing out in the cold with no hat on?
- 你吃了吗 - 吃了
- Did you get something to eat? - Yeah, I already ate.
好的
All right.
- 你有点晚了 知道吗 - 我可以自己照顾自己
- You're late, you know. - I can take care of myself.
小玛丽
Yo, Little Marie!
你不打算给你的孩子介绍我了
Ain't you gonna introduce me to your kid?
- 小史 你好吗 - 有什么事
- How you doing, Steps? - What's up?
听好了 我有一间餐厅
Listen, I got this place,
一间小小的食堂 离这儿不远
this restaurant, nice little eatery not too far from here.
这是什么垃圾 是一餐巾
What's all this junk? Got a tissue.
有时候觉得自己是一只袋鼠 满袋子的东西
Sometimes I feel like a kangaroo, all the stuff in my pocket, you know.
这是你的 我有张名片 在这里
Here you go. I got a card, there it is.
假如你有空的话 你们俩
And if you ever get a chance, it'd be great...
都能来坐坐 吃吃东西多好
...if both of youse come down there and eat.
那样就好 是免费的 要不这样 我把卡片留在这里 这里
It'd be great, free. You know. Anyway, I'll leave it over there... Here.
我会把它留在台阶上 小史
I'll leave it on the steps. Steps.
迟点见
See you later.
来 走吧
Come on, let's go.
从你十岁开始 你知道什么对你来说是最好的
You've known what's best for you since you were 10.
从你独自一人进来以后
Since you walked in here alone.
钱可以买到很多东西
Got everything money can buy...
除了一样之外
...except what it can't.
那就是自尊 自尊是你走出去的理由
It's pride. Pride is what got your ass out of here.
失败是让你回来的理由
Losing is what brung you back.
像你这样的人 他们要接受考验 需要一次挑战
But people like you, they need to be tested. Need a challenge.
不会有的 没有什么人能打败我
That ain't gonna happen. Ain't nothing out there.
总有人比你强 总有
There's always somebody out there. Always.
当那个时刻来临 你找到站在你面前
When that time comes and you find something...
屹立不倒的选手
...standing in front of you that ain't running...
一步也不会退后 朝你一直攻击
...that ain't backing up, hitting on you,
你累到连呼吸都困难了
and you're too damn tired to breathe...
你找到那样的感觉就对了
You find that situation on you, that's good.
那就是火焰下的考验
Because that's baptism under fire.
你熬过了 你就找到这个世界上
You get through that, you find the only kind of respect...
值得你珍惜的东西
...that matters in this damn world:
自尊
Self-respect.
谢谢你 马丁 感激你这席话
Thanks, Martin. I appreciate that.
现在 你想冠军为你做点什么
Now, what can the champ do for you?
给点我你赚的钱
You can give me some of that money you got.
- 你知道吗 我喜欢你 马丁 - 也没那么喜欢
- You know, I like you, Martin. - But not that much.
你说对了
Exactly.
和小孩合照一张好吗
How about a picture with the kid? All right?
当然可以
Sure.
来吧 小子 紧握拳头 让你看上去更凶狠
Here, son, hold up your fist. Makes you look more hazardous.
- 你的 - 谢谢 洛奇
- There you go. - Thanks, Rock.
慢慢吃
Enjoy your meal.
- 他人很好吧 - 洛奇
- He's a nice guy, isn't he? - Rocky?
- 是的 - 斯拜德刚下楼了
- Yeah. - Spider just went downstairs.
- 我不知道那样好不好 - 他在那里干什么
- I don't know if that's all right. - What's he doing?
我也不知道 那是你朋友
I don't know. That's your friend.
斯拜德
Yo, Spider!
- 让我来洗碗吧 这样我会好过些 - 别这样 你是我的客人
- Let me do some dishes. I feel better. - Come on. You're my guest.
- 让我做些事吧 - 吃东西就行了 客人都是那样的
- Let me do something. - Keep eating. Guests do that.
别让我和你再打一场 上次你只是走运了
Don't make me fight you again. Last time you got lucky.
走运？ 好的
Lucky? Okay.
上帝要我工作
Jesus wants me to work.
- 洛奇 - 什么事
- Yo, Rocky. - Yeah?
你有客人
You've got guests.
别弄湿自己 好吗
Don't get too wet, okay?
还好上帝没叫你烧菜
Glad Jesus didn't ask you to cook.
你留下卡片了
You kept the card.
是的 卡片留下了
Yeah, I kept the card.
- 快坐 - 好的
- Why don't you sit down? - Yeah, sure.
因为 你知道吗 我走进去 然后说早上好 用这个表情
Because, you know what, I walk in there, I say good morning, I do this:
今晚 又是关于拳击的
Tonight, boxing once again.
两个打法完全不同的选手
Two contrasting styles in almost every way.
你能把电视调大声点吗 请调一下
Hey, can you turn this up? Turn this up, please.
谁是永远的强者 如果两个不同时代的选手站在同一
Who was the best of all time? If two athletes from different eras...
擂台上 谁会取得最终胜利呢
...could compete against one another, who would come out on top?
同一规则下 同一拳套下 谁是最棒的
Given the same rules, using the same equipment, who was the greatest?
我们把数据输入电脑
We feed our facts into the computer.
他们称体重准备一决高下的同时
They weigh in on who they think will reign supreme...
杰出的体育专栏作家小组为您送上 专业评论
...while fielding the comments of our illustrious panel of sportswriters.
冠军
Champ!
- 冠军 - 怎么了
- Yo, champ! - Yeah?
快来看看这无聊节目 他们在谈论你
Come check out this trash they're talking about you, man!
- 你在说些什么 - 来看看 快
- What you talking about? - Come check this out. Hurry up.
今晚 两个时代的重量级拳击世界冠军
Tonight, the former two-time heavyweight champion...
从费城来的洛奇·巴尔博亚
...from Philadelphia, Rocky Balboa.
好的 美国周刊的澈卡·庄逊 你怎么看
All right, Chuck Johnson, USA Today?
毫无疑问 洛奇·巴尔博亚在拳击运动不很
There's no question that Rocky Balboa fought tougher fights...
完善的时代打出强悍的风格
...during a tougher era in boxing.
分析一下梅森的职业生涯就知道
You look at Mason Dixon in his career...
他基本上以消耗敌人体力为战术
...he's basically been spoon-fed his opponents.
在我心中 毫无疑问 洛奇不只是随随便便赢
No question in my mind. Not only does Rocky win...
他彻底击倒对手取得胜利
...but he wins knockout.
洛奇
Rocky!
后代
Offspring.
伯纳德·费楠德斯 你怎么看
Bernard Fernandez?
迪克逊是他统治的拳击界的受害者
Dixon is a victim of his own dominance.
他从来没经历过 需要倒下再爬起的比赛
He's never been in real knockdown-dragout brawls.
他从不需要发挥真正实力 调整状态
He never had to dig down to rally back.
假如他在和巴尔博亚一站中 发挥实力
If he tries to dig down against Balboa...
他会发现他的实力与对手相差甚远的
...he'll find he doesn't have a big enough shovel.
我显然支持巴尔博亚
I clearly give it to Balboa.
你说刚才怎么了
What happened to you? What happened to you?
拳击历史专家 伯特·阮道夫·舒嘉
Boxing historian Burt Randolph Sugar.
迪克逊一直在和懦夫战斗 我们不知道他到底有多强
Dixon has fought cream puffs. We don't know what he's made of.
在他们都年轻的时候 要加入这个条件
But both in their primes, you gotta factor in...
迪克逊的速度一流
...Dixon's unbelievable speed...
他冲劲十足的攻击足以抵挡巴尔博亚的攻击
...his slashing offense. He cuts Balboa to bits.
毫无疑问 迪克逊比较有希望赢
No doubt. Dixon wins all the way.
我们的分析到此结束 让我们一起来看看电脑分析的结果
Here's where our subjectivity ends. Let's see what the computer says.
迪克逊向巴尔博亚猛攻 洛奇没有反击 巴尔博亚在吃拳头
Dixon unloads on Balboa. Rocky has no answer. Balboa is eating jabs.
- 这是谁的时代 - 梅森的时代
- What time is it? - Mason time.
现在迪克逊完了 他在一直往后退 他快站不起来了
Now Dixon is done. He is reeling. He is almost out on his feet!
巴尔博亚把场子弄得火爆起来 围着场边一直击打他
Balboa turning up the heat. Pounds him across the ring.
伙计 这次他选错对手了 相信我
Boy, he's bit off more than he can chew this time. Believe it.
天啊 致命的右钩拳 迪森倒下了
Oh, a murderous right hook! And Dixon is out on his feet.
在他摔下地板的一刻 他失去了知觉
He is out cold as he crumbles to the canvas.
巴尔博亚嬴得了这场比赛
And it is Balboa who has won...
女士们 先生们 小洛奇 小洛奇
Ladies and gentlemen, Baby Rocky. Baby Rocky.
你喜欢那里的食物我很高兴
I'm glad you liked the food.
你把那些东西加热后 会是一顿漂亮的早餐
If you heat that up, it's pretty good in the morning.
是吗 谢谢 伙计
Yeah, thanks, man.
你孩子不错 我希望这样的音乐不会让你头痛
Nice kid. I hope this music ain't giving you a headache.
我喜欢怀旧的音乐
I like this old stuff.
我 我喜欢 很不错
No, I like it. It's nice.
那样就好
Well, good. Good.
你觉得小史想要一份工作吗 在周末赚点钱
Yo, you think Steps wants a job? Make a few bucks on the weekend?
自己赚钱是件好事 我孩子周末帮我工作 他存了些钱了
It's good making your own G's. My kid stashed a few bucks doing that.
你对我们为什么那么好
Why are you being so nice?
我不知道 我没非分之想 你知道的
I don't want you to think nothing's off, you know.
我的妻子 他离开我了 但不是真的离开 你懂我的意思吗
My wife, she's gone, but she ain't. You know what I mean?
是的 其实我也不是在想那些 相信我
Yeah, well, I wasn't thinking that. Believe me.
- 不是吗 那你在想什么 - 不
- No? Then what was you thinking? - No.
你又没欠我什么 你想干吗
That you don't owe us nothing. What are you doing?
耐心点
Be patient.
现在
Now...
我没欠你什么 但你为什么不
...I don't owe you nothing, but why do you gotta...
欠些东西 去啊
...owe something to get...
瞧
Bingo.
你为什么不欠点东西以此得到点什么呢 我是说真的
Why do you gotta owe something to get something, you know? Really.
我想和你的孩子出去一下 你觉得怎样
I think hanging out with your kid would be nice. What do you think?
我觉得那样不错
I think that'd be nice.
好的 你人真好
Good. That's very nice.
谢谢你的来访
I'm glad you come by.
看着你们吃得那么开心真好
It was nice watching you eat.
你和你孩子感情真好
Good company.
小玛丽 让那里光明点
Yo, Little Marie. Let there be light!
- 你喜欢狗吗 - 狗？
- You like dogs? - Dogs?
狗 这里是狗的世界 这里是他们存放
Dogs. This is like a dog pound. It's where they keep...
各种各样狗的地方 过去我常常来这里参观
...a large variety of dogs. I used to come here all the time for sightseeing.
但 你也知道 你在和狗交流的时候学到不少东西
But, you know, you learn a lot talking to dogs.
- 真的 你可以学到东西 所以 - 是的
- Really, you do. - Yeah, man. So...
伙计 这个怎样
Hey, man, how about this one?
它看上去不怎么友善 伙计
He don't look too friendly, my friend.
伙计 就这只吧 小狗 你好吗
Man, this is the one. Hey, boy, how you doing?
这只怎么样 过来啊 小狗
Hey, what about this one here? Come here, boy.
- 哪只 它？ - 是的 它挺好的
- Who, him? - Yeah, why not?
不 老兄 那是只丑狗
Hell, no. That is one ugly dog, man.
我知道 这狗丑得可爱 你近看一下它的毛色
I know, but it's kind of a cute ugly. If you look at it closely, the color...
看上去像旧家具 有点海盗宝箱的感觉
...it looks like old furniture, like some kind of pirate-chest thing going on.
好的 你说得很好 伙计 年轻一点的那只怎么样
Yeah, sure, man. Hey, so how about a young one?
小史 忘了那只吧 过来这里 我想你看看
Steps, forget him. Come over here. I want you to see something.
现在 你注意到那只动物 躺在那儿在做什么吗
Now, you notice what this animal is doing here? Lying in that position?
它什么也没做啊
He ain't doing nothing.
没有 它做了很多事情 它没有花一点能量
No, he's doing a lot. He ain't wasting no energy.
因为它死了
Because he's dead.
它没死 它的命还长着呢
He ain't dead. There's a lot of good mileage left on that animal.
给它点好吃的 给它个伴 砰！它又充满力量了
Good food, the addition of a couple of new friends, bingo, he's back.
- 你觉得叫它什么好呢 - 狗是你的 你取吧
- What do you think is a good name? - It's your dog. You name him.
不 这只狗是我们一起养的 一人一半
No. It's, like, a community animal. Fifty-fifty.
听着 我不是很了解狗
Look, I don't know much about no dogs.
其实也不是那么复杂的
Well, it ain't that complicated.
你养它 喂它 自然让它长
You pet him, you feed him, and nature takes its course.
你也知道的 你不想为你的宠物取名字吗
You know, so... Don't you wanna name an animal?
每个人至少为一个动物命名
Every guy should at one time try to name an animal something.
我也不知道叫什么合适 睡包好吗
I don't know. Fleabag?
是个容易记得的名字 没创造性 但很不错的建议
It's catchy. It ain't original, but it's pretty good.
我觉得你可以来点青年人的名字
I think you could come up with, in your young brain...
比睡包说出来更好听的名字
...something better to throw out than Fleabag.
小爆头怎么样
Punchy. How's that?
- 小爆头 - 好的 就叫小爆头
- Punchy? - Yeah, Punchy.
- 我很喜欢这个名字 你知道吗 - 真的
- I like it, you know. - For real?
是 真的 就叫小爆头 容易记 又容易写
Yeah, for real. Punchy it is. It's easy to remember, it's not that hard to spell.
听一次 就记住了 小爆头 很好
And once it's in your brain, you never forget it. Punchy. Very good.
- 好的 伙计 - 叫得好
- All right, man. - Good call.
好的 小爆头 你准备好出来了吗 我的朋友
All right, Punchy. You ready to get bailed out, my friend?
好了
Okay.
你知道那是开玩笑的吧 对吗
Hey, you know it was a joke, don't you?
是的 我知道 你很风趣
Yeah, I know. You're a very funny guy.
洛奇？
Rocky?
拳击迷们的反应让他知道 他们不是那么满意
The fans let him know how they feel about it.
- 抱歉 离开一下 - 好的
- Excuse me. - Sure.
粉丝们的反应可能会带来坏影响
This could get ugly.
- 小洛 - 保利
- Rock. -  Yo, Paulie.
他们待儿会讨论那场奇怪的电视比赛
They're gonna be talking about that fake Looney Tune fight.
伙计 我们快要送上 今天的特色菜了
Hey, come on. We're about to serve today's special.
墨西哥菜改改名字换成意大利菜 一点都不特别
Italian food cooked up by a bunch of Mexicans ain't so special.
我偷懒来看这个的
Hey, I skipped work for this.
哪来的丑狗
What an ugly dog.
它很可爱啊
It's a cute dog.
- 洛奇 - 什么事
- Hey, Rock. - Yeah?
我想离开一下 你的奖状照片之类的东西很酷
I'm gonna take off. That stuff back there is pretty cool.
- 你喜欢吗 - 是的 伙计
- Oh, you like that? - Yeah, man.
- 谢谢 谢谢你 - 待会见
- Thanks, I appreciate it. - I'll catch you later.
好的
All right.
- 那个犯罪分子是谁 - 他是个好孩子
- Who's the criminal? - He's a nice kid.
他穿得像流浪汉
He dresses like a bum.
他从人们装未洗衣服的篮子里出来 有够恭维的了
Coming from a human hamper, that's quite a compliment.
把值钱的银具收好
Hide the silverware.
谢谢
That's nice.
你好 斯拜德
Hey, Spider.
你不是打晕过他一次的吗
Didn't you knock out that bum once?
别再讨论这个了
Will you give it a rest?
就为了看这个我上班要迟到了 让我歇口气看看吧
I'm gonna be late for work for this. Give me a break, huh?
好的 就看几秒
All right. Just for a few seconds.
1960年末 一场相似的比赛 在两个传奇人物中爆发
In the late '60s, a simulated fight took place between two legends...
穆海穆德·阿里 和 洛奇·马烯亚诺
...Muhammad Ali and Rocky Marciano.
马烯亚诺退休已久 阿里不能够和他来场正式交战
Marciano long retired, and Ali unable to fight legitimately...
因为三年来 他的参军梦都遭拒绝
...for three years for having refused induction into the armed forces...
他急需钱来维持生活 便答应了一场所谓的梦幻比赛
...was in need of money, and agreed to the dream match...
比赛结果会由电脑决定
...whose outcome would be decided by a computer.
自从洛奇·马烯亚诺赢那场
It's almost 35 years since Rocky Marciano...
由电脑打分的比赛 已有三十五年了
...won the much-disputed computer decision...
你们知道吗 其实没多大变化
...and guess what? Not much has changed.
上周 洛奇·巴尔博亚嬴了一场毫无悬念的比赛
Last week, Rocky Balboa won a decisive fight...
看到了吗 那就是我跟你说的 卡通拳击
See? That's the cartoon fight I'm telling you about.
看到了
Yeah.
一记极好的拳
A stunning knockout.
可要记住了 比赛场上毫无人性可言
Keep in mind, this is taking the human factor out of it.
- 电脑显示巴尔博亚 - 漂亮
- The computer says Balboa... - Beautiful.
会取得胜利 13秒完胜 下面是这次比赛的余波
...would be triumphant, KO 13. And here's some of the fallout:
一个开始只是给人简单消遣的测试
What started as a simple form of entertainment...
已经变成认为像巴尔博亚这样的
...has become a rallying cry for people who think...
守旧打法的运动员可以取胜的人们的口号
...an old-school athlete like Balboa could actually be better.
电脑技术创造了些不可能的事 那只是毫不负责任的表现
Computer technology has to create what isn't. That's just not responsible.
去看看医生吧 你
Get therapy, will you?
你认为巴尔博亚与迪克逊交战 结果会如何呢
How do you think Balboa would have done against Dixon?
很难看 我个人认为 巴尔博亚 被过分高估了
Badly. Personally, I think Balboa was completely overrated.
他在费城南部开了一家餐厅
He owns a restaurant in South Philly.
那里有什么看点 被砸碎的鸡肉？
What's the specialty, pounded chicken?
总而言之 我会付钱看的 下一个话题 钠斯汽车联赛
Anyway, I would have paid to see the fight. Next topic, NAS CAR...
争议不断
...and the controversy that won't go away.
让我们回到周日的赛场
Let's go back to Sunday's race...
伙计 开心点
Hey, hey, hey, cheer up.
这可是免费宣传 别太在意 肉店叫我回去了
It's free advertisement. Come on. Meat house calls.
你好 罗伯特
Yo, Robert.
这么晚了 你还在外面干什么
What are you doing out so late?
我打电话给你了 但没人接
I tried calling, but nothing was picking up.
- 有什么事吗 - 我只是经过
- Is something wrong? - I just wanted to come by...
- 想见见你本人 - 想进去吗
- ...and see you in person. -  Wanna come inside?
不 我只想听听你的意见
No. I just wanna get your opinion on something.
好的 什么意见
Sure. Opinion on what?
他们说这附近你只会走一次
You know, they say you only go around once, right?
- 是的 我听过 - 那么
- Yeah, I've heard that. - Well...
我想做点什么
...I think I wanna, like, do something.
- 什么 - 打一打
- Like what? - Fight.
你也知道 不是很正规的 只是小打小闹
You know, nothing big. Small stuff, like locally. You know.
你不觉得你有点老了吗
Don't you think you're too, you know, old?
你觉得因为过多几次生日就
You think you ought to stop trying things...
放弃尝试 我不是那样的人
...because you had a few too many birthdays? I do not.
街坊会觉得你有问题的
People will think you're crazy.
真正疯狂的是与对手站在赛场上 然后说我准备好了
What's crazy about standing toe to toe saying, "I am," you know?
那只是你一厢情愿
That's just ego talking.
你想向别人证明点什么 老爸
What are you trying to prove to other people, Pop?
证明？听着 我的思维模式
Prove? Listen, I stopped thinking...
早就与现在的人脱节了
...the way other people think a long time ago.
你用现代人的眼光看我们
You gotta think like you think.
- 这是事实 - 真的吗 太好了
- I do. - Do you? Good.
你要面对现实啊 好吗 现在世界变了
You gotta face reality, okay? It's a different world now.
只是衣服变了
Only the clothes is different.
我不知道你想从我这里得到什么
I really don't know what you want from me.
我只是想进入你的世界 你也知道 像家人
I just wanted us to get involved. You know, like, home team.
无论你在想什么 你在经历什么 总会过去的
Look, whatever it is, whatever you're going through, it'll pass.
是的 你可能说对了
Yeah, you're probably right.
时代会赶上所有人的
Time is gonna catch up to all of us.
- 特别是当你站得稳的时候 - 别担心了
- Especially if you're standing still. - Hey, come on.
听着 我早上打电话给你好吗
Look, I'm gonna call you in the morning.
- 你告诉你孩子这些东西了吗 顺便问问 - 是的
- Did you tell this to your kid? - Yeah, I did.
- 他怎么想 你是疯子 对吧 - 是的
- What'd he think, you're nuts, right? - Yeah.
他不相信你吗 欢迎来到我的世界 伙计
Oh, well, he don't believe in you? Welcome to my world, buddy.
小洛 没有人给你头衔
Rocko, nobody's giving you no title shot.
我知道 我不想要
I know that. I don't want one.
这个不是一次精神折磨
So this isn't a mental disturbance?
不是
No.
你生气了 是因为他们贬低你的社会地位
You're mad because they took down your statue?
也不是
No.
讲真的 不是
Not really, no.
如果这是关于钱的 你在脖子上挂张牌 说 来打我
If it's about money, just hang a sign around your neck saying, "Punch me."
五美元一次 你会赚到大钱的
Five dollars, you'll make big money.
怎么了 你还没到达人生的高潮吗
What? You haven't peaked yet?
- 高潮？ - 是的 高潮
- Peaked? - Yeah, peaked.
我不知道怎么讲 在底下还有点东西
I don't know. There's still some stuff in the basement.
- 什么底下 - 心底
- What basement? - In here.
跟我说说
Tell me about the stuff.
- 这个怎么样 - 跟我说说
- What about it? - Tell me about the stuff inside.
- 是生气吗 - 生气？
- Is it angry? - Angry?
你生气是因为你太太离开你了吗
Are you mad because Adrian left you?
她不是离开了 保利 她死了
She didn't leave, Paulie. She died.
好的 好的 好的
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
你知道吗 有时候 连呼吸都困难
You know, sometimes it's hard to breathe.
你知道吗 我觉得有 一只野兽在我心里
You know, I feel, like, this beast inside me.
没事的 小洛 没事的 好吗
It's okay, Rocko. Please, it's okay.
真的 没关系吗
Is it okay?
我只是从来没想过 没有她日子会那么困难
I just never knew it was supposed to be this hard.
不应该是这样的 保利  你知道吗
It wasn't supposed to be like this, Paulie. You know, it...
你有空过来训练一下我吗
So you wanna come by and help me train?
我在这里有工作
I got a job here.
我了解
I understand.
你记得你说过 在一个地方待久了
Remember you said if you stay one place long enough...
你也成为那个地方了吗
...you become that place?
小洛 这就是我目前想做的
Rocko, this is all I got.
我理解 保利 我很理解
I understand, Paulie. I do.
假如你有空来看我训练的话 我会很感激你的
If you get time and come down and see me train, I'd appreciate it.
那当然 小洛
Of course, Rocko.
再见 保利
Bye, Paulie.
再见 小洛
Goodbye, Rocko.
保重 小洛
Take care, Rocko.
本次宾夕法尼亚州 运动委员会全体委员出席的会议
This plenary session of the Pennsylvania Athletic Commission...
目的在于审核洛奇·巴尔博亚的
...is convened in order to consider the application of Rocky Balboa...
自由拳击运动员牌照
...for the issuance of a discretionary professional boxing license...
此前由于法律不允许他获得牌照
...due to his ineligibility to be licensed as a matter of right.
巴尔博亚先生 欢迎你 由于代表自己来凌汛
Mr. Balboa, you're welcome here. Since you're representing yourself...
我们欢迎你来做开场白
...we invite you to make an opening statement, if you'd like to.
不了 我只是好奇而已
No, I was just curious how I did, that's all.
好的 药物测试局已经通知我们
All right, well, the Medical Advisory Board has informed us...
你提交的整套运动员测试
...that the battery of tests to which you've been subjected...
都通过了 而且很出色
...you've passed these tests with flying colors.
恭喜你
And we congratulate you for that.
- 谢谢 - 然而 我们这席人
- Thanks. - However, this commission...
出于好意 并不推荐你拿执照
...in good conscience, cannot recommend you for a license...
所以我们拒绝你的申请
...and we therefore deny your application.
- 我不是做了你们要求的吗 - 是的 你做到了
- Didn't I do what you asked? - Yes, you did.
所以我应该拿到牌照吧
So I should get a license, right?
不是那么简单的
Not exactly.
既然你们一开始就不给我通过
So why did you give me all
为什么还要求我做这些测试呢
them tests if you was never passing me?
我们要支持一下做的决定
We've gotta stand by our decision here...
就目前来讲要撤消你的请求
...and we have to deny your request for a license at this time.
我一点权利也没有吗
Yo, don't I got some rights?
你在指什么权利
What rights do you think you're referring to?
就好比一张正式文件
Like in that official paper they wrote down the street?
- 那是权利和自由法案规定的东西 - 权利和自由法案
- That's the Bill of Rights. - Bill of Rights.
上面不是说了要追求你喜欢的东西吗
Don't it say something about going after what makes you happy?
不 那只是追求幸福 不是法律范围 你的论点是什么
No, that's "the pursuit of happiness." But what's your point?
我的论点是我在追求些东西 没有人支持我
My point is I'm pursuing something, and nobody looks too happy about it.
我们只是为了你的利益着想
But we're just looking out for your interests.
那谢谢了 或许你为自己着想得多一些
I appreciate that, but maybe you're looking out for your interests more.
你不应该叫申请人到这里 交了款 递交了测试
You shouldn't ask people to come here and pay the freight on something.
还不行 你们觉得这样做对吗
They pay, it still ain't good enough. You think that's right?
或许这是你的工作 但你为什么要阻止我的工作
Maybe you're doing your job, but why you gotta stop me from doing mine?
如果你愿意经受所有考验 去获得你想要的
If you're willing to go through all the battling to get where you want to get...
谁有权利阻止你
...who's got the right to stop you?
或许你有些事还没完成 一些你想做的事
Maybe you got something you never finished, something you wanna do.
一些你没有向人交代的事
Something you never said to somebody, something!
你被人拒绝 即使在你尽力了之后
And you're told no, even after you pay your dues.
谁有权利否定你 谁？没有谁！
Who's got the right to tell you that? Who? Nobody!
倾听你的内心才叫权利 没有人有权利对你的内心说不
It's your right to listen to your gut. It's nobody's right to say no...
在你嬴取自己的权利后 你可以当你想当的人 做你想做的
...after you earn the right to be what you wanna be or do what you wanna do!
我年纪越大 我就会遗留更多东西 这就是生活
The older I get, the more things I gotta leave behind. That's life.
我叫你们留在桌上的唯一的东西 是正确的
The only thing I'm asking you guys to leave on the table is what's right.
伙计 看了今天的报纸了吗
Yo! Have you seen the paper today?
第一行 第一行
Front row. Front row.
太好了
That is so great.
- 好的 好的 - 去吃点东西吧 吃东西
- All right, all right. - Let's go get some food. Food.
- 去喝啤酒吧 来啊 - 来啊
- Let's get a beer. Come on. - Come on.
上次两场比赛早就被别人遗忘了
The last two pay-per-views were in the toilet.
你没在赚世界拳击冠军应该赚到的钱
You're not making heavyweight-championship money.
外面不出名的人多得是 小梅
There's a bunch of nobodies out there, Mase.
我想和你谈谈我们今后可采纳的机遇
I wanna talk to you about an opportunity we should run with.
看着我 你听说洛奇·巴尔博亚申请并拿到了执照吗?
Look at me. You heard Rocky Balboa applied for a license and got one?
- 是 我听说了 别管他 - 听我说 听我说
- I heard. Forget about him. - Hear me out.
你想让我跟一个我把双手绑在背后也能打得过的人比赛
You want me to fight a guy I can beat with both hands tied behind my back.
人人都知道你能打趴下他 但这不是关键
Everybody knows you could beat him sitting down. That's not what it's about.
关键是赚钱 我们要把那虚拟化的比赛变成资本
It's about making money. We gotta capitalize on that computer fight.
这是上百万的买卖 给你就有1500或2000W
This could do a million buys. That's 15, 20 million to you.
- 忘了吧 - 你到底想干什么 因为没人会再挤破门
- Forget it. - No one's beating the door down...
- 来看你比赛了 - 听着 老大 我们需要有保证的比赛
- ...to watch you fight anymore. - We got guaranteed fights.
没什么有保证的比赛 你想在你朋友面前比赛吗 我们来吧
You wanna do this now in front of your friends, we'll do it now.
我们什么也没有 所有的你想参与的比赛都被拒绝了
We got nothing. All the pay-per-view fights you come up with got rejected.
想知道为什么吗
You know why?
外面到处都是无家可归的流浪者 没人关心他们
They're all bums out there. Nobody cares about them.
没有市场价值了 但是巴尔博亚的这件事很有意思
There's no marquee value. But this Balboa thing is interesting.
- 我不想干 - 听我说
- I don't wanna do it. - Listen to me.
这是一个"有过什么"决不是"会有什么的"世界
It's a has-been, never-gonna-be world.
你可以称之为怀旧 或无论什么
Call it nostalgia, whatever you want...
但人们总是和那有联系 这不会损失什么 挺好的
...but people relate to that stuff. This is a no-lose. It's all good.
- 对谁好 - 你! 不是我! 你!
- Good for who? - For you! Not for me! For you!
等下 也许你不明白 人们不喜欢你了
Maybe you don't understand. People don't like you no more.
他们不再追捧你了 他们不再支持你了 明白不
They don't follow you. They're not supporting you anymore. Understand?
别好像我玷污了你的传统似的
Don't look at me like I'm messing with your legacy.
每个运动员都认为自己有传统
Every jock now thinks they got a legacy.
传统是你能赚到钱而不是如何花钱 这就叫传统
A legacy is what you get instead of getting paid. That's a legacy.
- 哥们 别跟我说话好像我傻似的 - 没 没 我不说了
- Don't talk to me like I'm stupid. - I'm not no more.
人人都知道你能海扁这老家伙 但你没有
Everybody knows you could kick this old man's ass. But you don't.
给他稍稍留点尊严 人们就会说
Leave him with a little dignity, so they say:
梅森·迪克逊真有同情心 真是好样的 好人
"Mason Dixon's got compassion. He's a decent guy, he's a nice guy."
你就会有新的追随者 我们可以把我的钱翻倍
You get a whole new audience, we'll double your money.
你想有个新的形象吗 那你就这么做吧
You want a new image? That's how you get it.
来取代你俩给建立的形象吗
To replace the one that you two made?
等等 我们给你铺的路 是你自己搞的
Whoa, wait. We made your world green. You made the rest.
都是你 你导致那些垃圾事发生的
This is you. You made all this junk happen.
我受不了这乱七八糟的了
I've had it up to here with this mess.
是时候做些改变了 我要去马丁的体育馆
Time for me to make changes. I'm going to Martin's gym.
- 我们一会再谈吧 - 忘了这些废话吧
- We'll talk about it. - Forget this crap.
我想马丁 回来 没什么可谈的了
I want Martin back. There's nothing to talk about.
- 你好啊? - 真是惊喜
- How you doing? - Hey, what a surprise.
我开车到附近 然后我想
I was driving around the neighborhood, I thought...
- 为什么我不开车过来打个招呼呢 - 想进来吗
- ...why not drive by and say hello? - You wanna come inside?
不了 狗狗得锻炼下 你想散散步吗
No, the dog needs some exercise. You wanna take a little walk?
- 恩 恩 好的 - 户外很好
- Yeah, yeah. All right. - It's nice outside.
- 好的 - 舒服又凉快
- All right. - Nice and brisk.
什么时候弄的只狗?
When did you get a dog?
我们几天前买的小爆头
We picked up Punchy a couple of days back.
- 小爆头? - 恩
- Punchy? - Yeah.
你叫你的狗小爆头?
You named your dog Punchy?
你儿子想的名字
Your kid come up with the name.
啊? 我想这有点失礼了
Oh, yeah? I think that's disrespectful.
不 不 挺好 真的
Oh, no, no. It's fine, really.
不 很容易记 挺好的 你要知道
No, it's easy to remember and it's all that, you know.
听着 来饭店你认为怎么样
Listen, what do you think about coming over to the restaurant?
- 干什么? - 那个 你知道 来 好像...
- What for? - Well, you know, for, like...
上班 女服务员要生孩子了 你会做的很好的
For work. The hostess is gonna be having a kid. You'd do good.
- 我不确定 - 我来告诉你 你会做的很好的
- I don't know. - I'm telling you, you'd do so good.
我很感激你为我儿子做事 但是我不能
I appreciate what you're doing for my kid, but I can't.
听着 我认为你会喜欢的
Hey, listen, I think you'd like it a lot.
那环境很好 很让人舒心
It's a nice environment, it's very pleasant.
好吧 我们能不谈吗?
Yeah, can we drop it?
有什么困难吗?
What's bothering you?
没 挺好的 那个 我要回去了
Nothing. It's all right. Listen, I gotta get back.
- 不 不好 - 哦 算了
- No, it ain't all right. - Oh, come on.
- 怎么? - 我将是人们进来...
- What? - I'm gonna be the first person...
- ...看见的第一个人? - 你发递菜单就行
- ...people see when they walk in? -  You give out menus.
说"欢迎光临" 给客人找座
You say, "Hello, how are you?" You sit people down.
你看 假如我能做 人人都可以做
Look, if I can do it, anybody can do it.
你能找到10个100个更好的人来干这工作
You could find 10 better people, a hundred better people for this job.
试下吧 就2周
Give it a try, like two weeks.
我不想试
I don't wanna try.
- 谁给你装进了这思想? - 没人
- Who put this stuff in your head? - Nobody.
这种思想不会自己在脑子里出现
Well, it just don't get in there by itself.
谢谢来看我
Thanks for coming by.
你最后一次跳舞是什么时候? 有一段时间了吗?
Yo, when was the last time you went dancing? Has it been a while?
- 为什么这么问? - 是因为你和这些难题可以跳舞
- Why are you asking? - I'm asking because...
你也许也可以和我一起跳
...you dance around these problems, you might as well dance with me.
我也许跳的不太好 但怎么也比熊强吧
I ain't that good, but I'm better than the average bear.
这出自哪 我忘了
Where that came from, I don't know.
- 你疯了 - 有点
- You're crazy. - A little bit.
但是你想和谈话的方式 也有点疯狂
But the way you're thinking and talking, it's a little crazy too.
来吧 你挺好的 真的 过来吧
Come on, you deserve better. Really. Come on over.
我需要你来把我地方分分类 费城需要你
I need you to class my place up. Philly needs you.
假如你再要说"X 你, 人渣"我完全理解
And if you say, "Screw you, creepo" again, I totally understand.
但是我警告你 我要站在...
But I'm warning you, I'm gonna put myself...
...这的街道中心...
...in the middle of the street here...
...我和小爆头 朝第一辆共车喊:
...and stand here, me and Punchy, and wave to the first bus, say:
"过来 碾碎我吧!
"Come on over here and mash me!
小玛丽拒绝了饭店的工作.
Little Marie turned down the job at the restaurant.
她认为比我们都强''
She thinks she's better than us."
真的? 呵呵 这已经20年没公车了
Oh, yeah? Well, there hasn't been a bus down here in 20 years.
- 真的? - 恩
- Yeah? - No.
大概是利润很低
That was a close call.
真的 来吧 会好的
Listen, seriously. Come on over. It'd be nice.
行吧
All right.
保利!
Paulie!
抱歉 保利
Sorry, Paulie.
抱歉
Sorry.
你好? 把我的不寻常的东西放这儿
How are you? Get my unusual up there.
不好意思 快递放后面
Excuse me. Deliveries are in the back.
我不是送快递的
I'm not a delivery guy.
那 你定座了吗?
Well, do you have a reservation?
我像是个疯狂的印第安人吗?
Do I look like a freaking Indian?
洛克 洛奇?
Hey, Rock? Rocky?
我想我们这出了点麻烦
I think we've got a little bit of a problem with this guy.
麻烦? 不 不 他是熟人
Problem? No, no, he's just a relative.
好吧
Oh, okay.
保利
Yo, Paulie.
- 你眼睛怎么了? - 我打的
- What happened to your eye? - I hit it.
- 为什么? - 必须打
- Why? - Needed to.
发生什么了?
What happened?
- 我庆祝呢 洛克 - 怎么了?
- I'm celebrating, Rock. - Why?
- 光荣退休 - 退休?
- I retired. - Retired?
那么他们什么时候开始给退休的人猪肉了...
So when did they start giving retired people meat...
...而不是表 保利?
...instead of watches, Paulie?
我不需要表
I don't need a watch.
我有表! 你给我了一块表!
I got a watch! You gave me a watch!
保利…
Paulie...
我他妈不需要表.
I don't need no goddamn watch.
- 保利. - 我有一块表!
- Yo, Paulie. - I got a watch!
我有两块呢!
I got two watches!
保利!
Yo, Paulie!
保利.
Yo, Paulie.
洛克
Rock.
让人重返赛场是很需要勇气的 认识到自己会受到打击
It takes guts climbing back in that ring, knowing you're gonna take a beating.
你能做好的 洛克
You're gonna do all right, Rocko.
你怎么知道?
How do you know that?
地下室里的东西
The stuff in the basement.
谢了 保利
Thanks, Paulie.
- 嘿 - 嘿 洛克 你好
- Hey. - Hey, Rock, how are you?
- 你还好吗? - 恩 挺好的 你哪?
- You okay? - Yeah, good. How are you?
- 恩 好 好极了 - 好
- Yeah, fine. This is great. - Good.
那有人想和你谈谈
Listen, some guys over there wanna talk to you.
- 好的 谢谢你 - 好的?
- Okay. You got it. - Okay?
- 谢谢赏脸 十分感激 - 别客气
- Thanks for coming by. I appreciate it. - Our pleasure.
- 想听故事? - 哪种故事?
- Wanna hear stories? - What kind of stories?
很多人来想听听我打拳的故事
Well, a lot of people like to hear these old fight stories.
- 过会儿吧 - 好的
- Maybe later. - Okay.
我叫路·迪拜勒 这是埃索·卢加
I'm Lou DiBella. This is L.C. Luco.
他是梅森·迪克逊的经理人
He's Mason Dixon's manager.
- 为什么你不坐下和我们聊聊? - 好啊
- Will you sit down and join us? - Sure.
你知道 我们有奖励的合同关于梅森·迪克逊...
You know, we have the promotional contract for Mason Dixon...
- ...他是你的拳迷 - 真的?
- ...who's a big fan. - Really?
当他听说你有兴趣打拳...
When he heard you were interested in fighting...
...他想你为什么不试试?
...he thought why not try to work something out?
比如特殊赛事 顶级的表演赛
Like a special event. Like a first-class exhibition fight.
- 为什么是我? - 他太TM崇拜你了
- Why me? - He respects the hell out of you.
行吗? 我们照直说了 那个虚拟的比赛太吸引人了
All right? And let's be honest, that computer fight got people curious.
- 这会很是有趣 - 我不太有兴趣...
- This could be very interesting. - I ain't interested...
... 在 象 胖揍和使人尴尬
...in getting, like, mangled and embarrassed.
不 那决不会发生 绝对
No, that's not gonna happen. Never happen.
说实话 我想参加...
Truthfully, I was thinking more on a, like...
...小型的 不显眼的比赛 你看 小的 不是大赛
...miniscule, small level. You know. Small fights, not big fights.
小型的 比如 本地的 你明白我说的吗?
Small fights. Things that... Local. You know what I mean?
主意不错 别考虑是大型的 考虑只是表演赛
Not a bad idea. Don't think of it as big. Think of it like an exhibition.
考虑这是荣誉拳击手对话 这是你喜欢的
Think of it as a glorified sparring session. Here's something you'll like.
我们将把部分门票捐给慈善机构
We're gonna donate a portion of the gate to charity.
- 这总是不错的 - 给予总是好的
- That's always nice. - It's good to give.
恩
Yeah.
在哪比赛?
Where's it taking place?
- 拉斯维加斯 - 拉斯维加斯
- Las Vegas. - Las Vegas.
舒适又温暖 这冷的能整死你
Nice and warm. This cold's gotta be killing you.
- 有点僵硬 - 暖活点你会移动的更好
- Little stiff. - You move better when you're warmer.
- 恩 - 另外...
- Yeah. - And if nothing else...
...你又有新的故事可讲了
...you'll have new stories to tell.
- 我确实觉得该考虑下了 - 的确
- I really gotta think about this. - Absolutely.
- 可以吗? - 我理解 没问题
- Is that okay? - I understand. No problem.
我要过去那边 你可以点些吃的
I'm gonna go over there. You can order something.
- 你推荐什么? - 还都能吃
- What do you recommend? - It's all edible.
好的 谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
我们说服他了 想像迪克逊 遇见这王八蛋在他状态好的时候?
We got him. Imagine if Dixon met this bastard in his prime?
- 他会杀了他 杀了他 - 真没开玩笑
- He'd kill him. Kill him. - You ain't kidding.
哥们 有点迷惑了
Man, I'm confused.
我不认为这会发生
I didn't think this was gonna come along.
但这就是你想要的 不是吗?
But this is what you wanted, right?
我不知道 你知道 我天天讲啊讲
I don't know. You know, I talk and I talk.
有时我认为我说的就是真的...
Sometimes I think what I'm saying is true...
...但当我看我自己时 我又不确定真的是什么
...and then I look at myself and I'm not even sure what is true anymore.
因为这就像 我产生了关于打拳的疯狂的念头
Because it's like, I pushed this crazy idea about fighting.
我的意思是 这些都是干什么?
I mean, what's it all about?
我真的关心近距离近战和其他的什么吗...
Do I really care about standing toe to toe and all that stuff...
...或者 就像我孩子说的 自我
...or, like my kid says, is it just, like, ego?
或者我就是用新痛代替旧伤的老拳师?
Or am I this old pug who's just trying to replace old pain with new pain?
我不知道 真的不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
你看 我知道我平常说的不多
Look, I know I usually don't say a lot.
我总是听和看
I'm always listening and looking.
但是你是谁 你的一部分充满了生活...
But who you are, the part of you that's so full of life...
...我们都能感觉到 那团火...
...we all have that feeling, that fire...
...却没有机会来用它 然后它就消失了
...but usually never get a chance to use it. And then it just goes away.
但是你能 你有这机会 那就去做吧 为什么不呢?
But you can. You've got this opportunity, so do it. Why not?
我的意思是这就是 你一直以来的样子
I mean, this is who you are. This is who you'll always be.
而且你不用为任何人让路 除非你真的想走
And you don't move aside for nobody until you're ready to move.
别人怎么看这件事并不重要
And it doesn't matter how this looks to other people.
重要的是你的看法
All that matters is how it looks to you.
洛奇
Rocky.
洛奇 看着我
Rocky, look at me.
你的看法
How it looks to you.
假如这是你想做的事...
And if this is something that you wanna do...
...假如这是你要做的 那你就去做
...and if this is something that you gotta do, then you do it.
斗士就是要战斗
Fighters fight.
你不是想揍我吧 啊?
You're not gonna punch me, are you?
我要走了 呆的太久了 明天见
Listen, I gotta go before I wear out my welcome. I'll see you tomorrow.
谢谢
Thanks.
斗士要战斗 对吧?
Fighters fight, right?
举办比拳赛还要大型的活动是很难得的 这是
It's rare when you get to promote an event bigger than boxing. This is.
技术与意志的比拚 部分收益将捐给慈善机构
Skill versus will, with part of the proceeds going to charity.
梅森·迪克逊的好主意 来纪念过去的重量级拳王
The brainchild of Mason Dixon, to honor past heavyweight champions.
如洛奇·巴尔博亚一样的战士 我们现在开始发问
Warriors like Rocky Balboa. Let's open it up for questions.
冠军!
Hey, champ!
一些伟大的拳击手 在他们50多岁还比赛 下场惨痛
A few great fighters have fought in their 50s, often with disastrous results.
为什么你要冒着危险和困窘的危险比赛?
Why risk the danger and embarrassment?
消息灵通人士说你事实上没机会赢
The smart money says you have virtually no chance.
拳击手总是有机会的 这场比赛会很有竞争性的
A puncher always has a chance. This fight will be competitive.
你为什么这么做 洛奇?
Why are you doing this, Rocky?
我不知道 我更喜欢 做我十分喜欢做的 而不是…
I don't know, I'd rather do something I love badly than...
做一些我不喜欢的事而感觉很糟
Than to feel bad by not doing something you love.
洛奇 媒体都称你为发酵的巴尔博亚
Rocky, the press has labeled you a Balboasaurus.
对于这你是怎么看的?
How do you feel about that?
梅森 让我们谈下以后发生的事:
Let's say the following happens:
你赢了 我们会说你把老头打败了
You win, we'll say you beat an old guy.
你败了 虽然不太可能 你就会成为以后的笑话
You lose, say a thumb in the eye, you'll be the joke of the decade.
你们都知道这不会发生 这仅仅是个表演赛
You all know that will never happen. This is only an exhibition.
以后别再大张旗鼓的搞这些了 有电脑搞就行了
Don't go trying to make more out of this than that computer tried.
这个运动不是已经够乱了吗 为什么还要搞这些马戏表演
Isn't this sport in enough trouble without these circus events?
- 下个问题 - 表面上看 这看起来好像...
- Next question. - On the surface, this looks like...
...毫无价值的拳击表演在 没有冒犯的意思...
...a cheap bit of ring theater between, no offense...
...过时的和一个有着可靠传统和...
...a has-been and a man whose own credible legacy...
...受欢迎性存在疑问的人
...and popularity is in doubt.
- 看点在哪儿? - 疑问?
- What's the upside? - Doubt?
看点? 我说...
Upside? I mean...
你什么意思 看点? 我的意思是 我必须做什么?
What do you mean, upside? I mean, what do I have to do?
你们都知道 我的战绩 33-0 有30击倒获胜.
You know, I'm 33-0 with 30 knockouts.
我在帮你们忙 我带来这个表演赛给你们看
I'm doing you people a favor. I'm having this exhibition for you.
你们过来这是为了嘲笑我? 我是冠军
You gonna get up here and make a mockery out of me? I'm the champ.
我的意思是 我生气了 这家伙会受伤的
I mean, I get pissed, this guy get hurt.
赛场上见
See you at the fight.
这家伙是个笑话 他会被打扁的
The guy's a joke. He's gonna get crushed.
- 快 谁在这 - 你好?
- Look who's here. - How you doing?
- 看到我爸了吗? - 他在后面
- Have you seen my father? - He's in the back.
这地方从来没有这么多人吃饭 真难以置信
This place has never served this many meals. It's unbelievable.
吃的还好吗? 真希望你都喜欢 好吗?
You're doing good? Hope you're enjoying everything, all right?
不好意思
Excuse me.
怎么样? 真高兴你顺路来
How you doing? Glad you come by.
我能跟你谈谈吗?
Can I talk with you?
- 当然 - 出去谈行吗?
- Sure. - Can we do it outside?
- 你真的想弄这个? - 对 明天开始训练
- So you're going through with this? - I start training tomorrow.
洛克 我找了些关系
Hey, Rock. I made some connections.
我能通过这赚些钱 广告
I can make some money on this, endorsements.
当然可以 做吧
Absolutely. Do that.
- 谢谢 洛克 好的 - 恩
- Thank you, Rock. Okay. - Sure.
- 比赛紧张吗? - 怕的要死
- So you nervous about the fight? - Scared to death.
- 你看起来并不害怕 - 呵呵 我并不像看起来那样
- You don't look scared. - Well, I ain't supposed to.
那你并不非要做这个
Then you don't have to do it.
是的 我想我需要
Yeah, well, I think I do.
你要知道 与你生活并不容易
You know, living with you, it hasn't been easy.
人们看到 但想的确是你
People see me but they think of you.
现在不仅这样 而且比以前更坏了
Now with all this going on, it's gonna be worse than ever.
- 事情并不非要这样 - 就是这样!
- It don't have to be. - Sure it does!
- 为什么? 孩子 你有很多东西啊 - 什么 我的姓?
- Why? You've got a lot going on, kid. - What, my last name?
那就是我找到像样的工作的原因
That's the reason I got a decent job.
那就是人们把我的事放在第一位办
That's why people deal with me in the first place.
现在我刚开始不需要这样了...
Now I start to get a little ahead...
...我开始有属于自己世界了 但是这事就发生了
...I start to get a little something for myself, and this happens.
现在 我求你能不能不参加这比赛了
Now, I'm asking you as a favor not to go through with this.
这对你不会是好结果 对我也不会是好结果
This is gonna end up bad for you, and it's gonna end up bad for me.
- 你认为我伤害了你? - 是 在某方面 是的
- You think I'm hurting you? - Yeah. In a way, you are.
那是我最不会做的事
That's the last thing I ever wanted to do.
我知道你不想 但是事情就是这样发展的
I know that's not what you wanna do, but that's just the way that it is.
你不管人们怎么想吗? 人们拿你作笑话...
Don't you care what people think? Doesn't it bother you that people...
...你不着急吗? 然后我也会被卷进来?
...are making you out to be a joke and that I'll be included in that?
你认为这样对吗? 啊?
Do you think that's right? Do you?
你不会相信这些的 但你过去就这么打
You ain't gonna believe this, but you used to fit right here.
我握着你 对你妈妈说:
I'd hold you up and say to your mother:
''这孩子会成为世界上最好的孩子
"This kid is gonna be the best kid in the world.
这孩子会成为比我认识的所有人都厉害的人物''
This kid is gonna be somebody better than anybody ever knew."
然后你长大了 健康又令人惊奇
And you grew up good and wonderful.
看你长大真是奇妙 每一天都像上天给我的特权
It was great just watching, every day was like a privilege.
然后到了你成人的时候了 承担起了你的世界...
Then the time come for you to be your own man and take on the world...
...你确实这样 但是沿着线的某处 你变了
...and you did. But somewhere along the line, you changed.
你不再是你了
You stopped being you.
你让人家戳着你脸告诉你你并不好
You let people stick a finger in your face and tell you you're no good.
当事情变得困难了 你开始寻找你要责怪的东西...
And when things got hard, you started looking for something to blame...
...如巨大阴影
...like a big shadow.
让我来告诉你些你已经知道的
Let me tell you something you already know.
这个世界不全是阳光和彩虹
The world ain't all sunshine and rainbows.
这是个非常刻薄和肮脏的地方 它不管你多么强壮...
It's a very mean and nasty place, and I don't care how tough you are...
...它会打倒你 跪倒在它面前
...it will beat you to your
你不反抗的话它会一直让你这样
knees and keep you there if you let it.
你 我 没人会像生活那样的重击
You, me or nobody is gonna hit as hard as life.
但关键不是你能打得多么厉害 而是你能承受多大的重击...
But it ain't about how hard you hit. It's about how hard you can get hit...
...然后一直向前走
...and keep moving forward.
你能承受多少和然后一直向前走
How much you can take and keep moving forward.
那就是赢的真谛!
That's how winning is done!
假如你知道自己的价值 那就去实现自己的价值
If you know what you're worth, go and get what you're worth.
但是你要能够承受重击 不是指着手指...
But you gotta be willing to take the hits, and not pointing fingers...
...说着你不是你想做的那样 因为他 她 或其他人!
...saying you ain't where you wanna be because of him or her or anybody!
懦夫才这样 而不是你! 你不该这样!
Cowards do that, and that ain't you! You're better than that!
我会一直爱你 无论...
I'm always gonna love you no matter what.
无论发生了什么
No matter what happens.
你是我的儿子 我的骨肉
You're my son and you're my blood.
你是我这辈子最好的东西
You're the best thing in my life.
但是除非你开始相信自己 你才会有个新的生活
But until you start believing in yourself, you ain't gonna have a life.
别忘了去看看你妈妈
Don't forget to visit your mother.
- 啊 这些真漂亮 - 恩
- Yeah, those are beautiful. - Yeah.
- 你早退了? - 没
- You get off early from work? - No.
我辞了
I left.
我不干了
I quit.
不干了 为什么?
Quit, why?
我不是很...
I wasn't very...
我不知道 就是... 我不适合那
I don't know, I just... I didn't fit in there.
我理解
I understand.
- 那么 你想做什么? - 现在?
- So, what are you gonna do? - Right now?
现在我更想跟你在一起
Right now I'd rather be with you.
可以吗?
Is that all right?
恩
Yeah.
我好久都没看比赛了
It's been a long time since I seen a fight.
你知道那儿的人好像都懂拳击...
You know all there is to know about fighting...
...所以我们没必要再走那条老路了
...so there's no sense us going down that same old road again.
打败那家伙 你需要速度 但你没有
To beat this guy, you need speed. You don't have it.
你的膝盖受不了重击 所以不能剧烈跑
And your knees can't take the pounding, so hard running is out.
你的颈部有关节炎 你还有钙沉积在...
And you got arthritis in your neck. And you've got calcium deposits...
...大部分关节 所以快速轻拳也用不了
...on most of your joints, so sparring is out.
我有那问题
I had that problem.
所以我们需要的是好的老式的钝击创伤
So what we'll be calling on is good old-fashioned blunt-force trauma.
大马力 有耐力 坚固的 打桩机的拳头...
Horsepower. Heavy-duty, cast-iron, pile-driving punches...
..会让他疼得哭爹喊娘
...that will have to hurt so much they'll rattle his ancestors.
每次你打他一下...
Every time you hit him with a shot...
...就好像他要亲吻特快火车
...it's gotta feel like he tried kissing the express train.
我们来开始制作杀伤力的炸弹
Yeah! Let's start building some hurting bombs.
- 你能做到 - 你能的 洛克!
- Yeah, you'll get it. - You can do it, Rocko!
变得更强!
Getting stronger!
- 起! 起! 起! - 加油!
- Up! Up! Up! - Come on!
起!
Go!
加油 洛克!
Come on, Rocko!
加油 加油 来打它们 打它们
Come on. Come on. Let's hit them. Hit them.
你能行的 洛克
You can do it, Rock.
变得更强!
Getting stronger!
- 起 起 起! - 冲! 冲!
- Up, up, up! - Go! Go!
好的!
All right!
洛奇·巴尔博亚  2 1 7 磅!
Rocky Balboa, 217!
无可争议的重量级冠军 梅森·迪克逊 2 2 1 磅 !
The undisputed heavyweight champion, Mason Dixon, 221!
非常感谢 我很感激 冠军 多谢
Thank you very much. I appreciate it, champ. Thanks a lot.
洛奇! 洛奇! 洛奇!
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
- 你知道这有多少钱吗? - 很多
- Know how much money is in this? - A lot of it.
想像试着清理这里
Imagine trying to clean this place.
- 不 真的 - 巴尔博亚!
- No, seriously. - Balboa!
哥们 马上就赶上你们 好吗?
You guys, I'll catch up with you all later, okay?
罗伯特 为什么不和我一起来?
Robert, why don't you hang with me?
- 最近怎样 冠军? - 很好
- How you doing, champ? - I'm good.
没有理由让我们俩在比赛中受伤
No reason for neither one of us to get hurt in this fight.
我会尽量撑着 使你不会丢脸
I'll do my best to carry you, make sure you save face.
没什么可丢脸的
There'd be no embarrassment.
但是我向你发誓 假如你试着压我 你打我 你伤了我...
But I promise you, you try to press me, you hit me, you hurt me...
..你打我下盘 偷袭我 我会把你打飞
...you hit me low, cheap-shot me, I'll get you out of there.
你知道 很多人来拉斯维加斯会输 我可不是
You know, a lot of people come to Vegas to lose. I didn't.
这已经结束了
It's already over.
没有什么结束了除非它真的结束了
Ain't nothing over till it's over.
这句话从那来的 80年代的?
What's that from, the '80s?
大概是70年代的
That's probably the '70s.
记住我说的就行了
Just remember what I said.
冠军
Hey, yo, champ.
你不怕吗?
Yo, ain't you a little scared?
我没怕过
I don't get scared.
我想你有点怕的话你就会更努力
I think you try a little harder when you're scared.
这句话以前对我管用
This is what has worked for me.
- 我可不怕 - 哦 真的 你不怕我?
- I ain't scared. -  Oh, yeah. You ain't scared of me?
来来 我看看你会啥 来
Come on, let's see what you got. Come on.
别打我 我很弱
Hey, don't hit me, I'm brittle.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
- 忙吗? - 我刚想事呢
- How you doing? - I was just thinking.
- 你想进来吗? - 不 不 不 挺好的
- Did you wanna come in? - No, no, no, it's okay.
我就是想...
I just wanted to...
...我不知道 路过来看看你 祝你明天好运
...I don' t know, come by and wish you good luck for tomorrow.
- 谢谢 - 恩
- Thanks. - Yeah.
我给你带了点东西
I brought you something.
我希望你不介意 我从饭店带来的
I hope you don't mind, I took it from the restaurant.
- 不 - 谢谢
- No. - Thanks.
艾德里安
Adrian.
对 我想她能保佑你没事
Yeah. Thought she would keep you safe.
对 对 她总给我带来好运
Yeah. Yeah, she always brought me luck.
恩
Yeah.
我想对你对我和我儿子做的事表示感谢
I wanted to say thanks for everything you've done for me and my kid.
你很伟大 还有...
You've been great and...
你知道 明天...
You know, tomorrow...
...你要证明最不能标志人的年龄是人的心脏
...you're gonna prove that the last thing to age on somebody is their heart.
- 我会尽力的 - 你去给他们看看
- I'll try. - You go show them.
谢谢
Thank you.
重量级拳王是
The heavyweight championship has been...
120年来最令人觊觎的头衔
...one of sports' most coveted titles for 120 years.
两界重量级拳王 洛奇·巴尔博亚
Two-time heavyweight champion Rocky Balboa...
费城的子弹头 拥有有名的坚固的下颚
...the Philadelphia slugger, renowned for his cast-iron jaw...
凶猛的攻击 和钢铁般的意志
...ferocious body attack and will of steel...
所有的这些使这小个的斗士的胜利
...all of which have carried the smaller fighter to victories...
和这些身体条件更好的对手
...over the years against physically superior opponents.
梅森·迪克逊 当今的重量级拳王保持者
And Mason Dixon, the current heavyweight title holder...
拥有着高速 决心 和所有斗士都想要的信心
...with all the speed, determination and confidence any fighter could want.
但是很多人都对他是否有 成为真的冠军的心表示怀疑
But many still question whether he has the heart of a true champion...
他从未被逼到山穷水尽 今晚 我们拭目以待
...never having been pushed to go the distance. Tonight, we find out.
我们在内华达州拉斯维加斯的曼德勒海湾会议中心
Here at the Mandalay Bay Event Center in Las Vegas...
来转播大家期望很久的争霸战
...for the much-anticipated showdown...
在 梅森·"分界线"·迪克逊
...between Mason "The Line" Dixon...
和洛奇·"意大利种马"·巴尔博亚
...and Rocky "The Italian Stallion" Balboa.
我是吉姆·兰普利 和 拉里·莫什特
Hello, I'm Jim Lampley with Larry Merchant
还有 马克斯·卡勒曼...
and Max Kellerman...
...住在拉斯维加斯的曼德勒海湾酒店 在那儿我们预测...
...live from the Mandalay Bay Hotel in Las Vegas, where we anticipate...
...这将是拳击史上最残酷和最引人注目的比赛
...one of the most outrageous and compelling events in boxing history.
不被人欣赏的重量级冠军 梅森·"分界线"·迪克逊...
The unappreciated heavyweight champion, Mason "The Line" Dixon...
不惜陪上自己的名誉
...putting his reputation on the line...
与传奇的前重量级拳王洛奇·巴尔博亚对决
...against legendary ex-champion, Rocky Balboa.
即使这样大多数人仍把着看作神圣化的拳击对话
Even though most see this as more of a glorified sparring session...
...这地方的能量已经可以导电了
...the energy in the room is electric.
拉里 为什么这次比赛被宣传成表演赛?
Larry, why is this billed as an exhibition?
臆测: 这样他们就不会称之为死刑
Wild guess: So they wouldn't have to call it an execution.
撒迦利亚的4章6节写道:"不是倚靠势力 不是倚靠才能...
Zacariah 4:6 says, "It is not by strength, not by might...
...乃是倚靠我的灵方能成事...
...but by his spirit we have already claimed the victory...
...万军之耶和华说"
...in our Lord Jesus Christ."
好运 洛奇
Good luck, Rocky.
谢了 斯拜德 我很感激
Thanks, Spider. Appreciate it.
没人指望什么  我想 已经过了青春颠峰期的...
Nobody's expecting much, I think, from the way-past-his-prime...
...前冠军 洛奇·巴尔博亚
...former champ, Rocky Balboa.
洛克 我想跟你谈谈
Rock, I gotta talk to you.
你看 我知道你有很多要发泄出来的
Look, I know you got a lot of stuff you gotta get out of your system.
今晚就这么做 好吗? 摆脱那tm野兽...
Tonight you do it. Right? Get rid of the damn beast...
...让那结束吧 一劳永逸 求你了 我爱你
...let it be done, once and for all. Please, I love you.
洛奇! 洛奇! 洛奇!
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
灯光亮了 嗡嗡声逐渐变成了咆哮声
There go the lights. The buzz is building toward a roaring crescendo.
那是谁唱的?
Where did that come from?
我告诉你 我爱辛纳屈
I told you. I love Sinatra.
他非常好 辛纳屈
He's very good, Sinatra.
- 我们走 - 很好
- Let's go. - Very good.
洛奇·巴尔博亚来了 战场上的退伍老兵...
And here comes Rocky Balboa, veteran of the wars...
...我们最后再为他来一次欢呼
...here for one more last hurrah.
没准是最后的晚餐吧 他就是主菜
Or the Last Supper, perhaps, with him as the main course.
这是什么音乐? 你开玩笑呢吧
What's that music? You can't be serious.
"厚望"? 讲的是祝愿的事
"High Hopes"? Talk about wishful thinking.
呵呵 也许没希望更加实际吧 但无论如何 人们挺喜欢的
Well, maybe no hopes is more realistic. Anyway, the crowd likes it.
快看那意大利种马 冷静又放松
Look at the Italian Stallion. Cool and relaxed.
洛奇是个注定了的失败者 所以他们根本不在乎
Rocky's an off-the-board underdog, and they don't care at all.
这是关于他的骄傲 尊严和他的拳头
This is about his pride and dignity and his punch, guys.
最后引以为傲的就是这家伙的拳头
The last thing to go is a guy's punch.
洛奇总是有着一个拳手的运气
Rocky always has that puncher's chance.
洛奇·巴尔博亚仍然是 就像你听到的 人们的拳王
Rocky Balboa is still, as you can hear, the people's champion.
预测 伙计们: 至少在前两回合...
Prediction, guys: For at least two rounds...
...迪克逊得忙下了
...Dixon's gonna have his hands full.
满两个回合? 房子里有个傻的乐观主义者
Two whole rounds? We have a cockeyed optimist in the house.
- 你好吗? - 人们想看些...
- How you doing? - The crowd wants to see...
...真的 或者至少
...something real, or at least...
洛奇·巴尔博亚刚刚问我好
Rocky Balboa just asked me how I'm doing.
我从小看这家伙比赛长大 从未想过能为他解说
I grew up watching this guy. I never thought I'd be calling one of his fights.
这真是难以置信 我是他的拳迷 受不了了
This is unbelievable. I'm a fan, I can't help it.
梅森·迪克逊出场了
Now here comes Mason Dixon.
梅森·迪克逊出现在拳击台上
Mason Dixon establishing his presence in the ring.
突然场边出现了对话场面
And suddenly now a conversation breaking out at ringside.
迈克·泰森大叫 梅森·"分界线"·迪克逊
Mike Tyson calling out Mason "The Line" Dixon.
- 你要掌握比赛 - 我是冠军
- You can't call no shots here. - I'm the champ.
你不能无为 这是慈善工作
You not doing nothing. This is charity work.
你和那侏儒一起比赛
You got that midget with you right there.
女士们 先生们 欢迎来到曼德勒海湾渡...
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Mandalay Bay...
...拉斯维加斯的娱乐场和圣地
...resort and casino of Las Vegas.
今晚的大事件...
And a special main event of the evening...
...10局令人兴奋的比赛...
...10 rounds of heavyweight excitement...
...通过内华达州竞技协会批准
...sanctioned by the Nevada State Athletic Commission.
当铃声响起 比赛将由裁判乔·科特斯掌控
And when the bell rings, the referee in charge of the action, Joe Cortez.
现在 数千记的观众...
And now, for the thousands in attendance...
...数百万的电视观众 女士们 先生们...
...and the millions watching around the world, ladies and gentlemen...
...比赛要开始了!
...let's get ready to rumble!
首先介绍的是 蓝角的是...
Introducing first, fighting out of the blue corner...
...穿着黑色和金色相间的 官方体重 2 1 7 磅
...wearing black with gold, official weight, 217 pounds.
他的职业生涯记录 57胜 54次击倒获胜...
His professional record, 57 victories including 54 knockouts...
... 23败 和 1平
...with 23 defeats and one draw.
他是费城的拳击骄傲...
He is the fighting pride of Philadelphia...
...两界世界重量级冠军...
...the two-time heavyweight champion of the world...
..."意大利种马"...
..."The Italian Stallion"...
...洛奇...
...Rocky...
...巴尔博亚!
...Balboa!
希望他脑袋被打暴
Hope he gets his head busted.
闭嘴
Shut up.
拳击台另一边的是 红角的...
Across the ring, fighting out of the red corner...
...蓝黑相间 官方体重 221磅
...wearing white with blue, official weight, 221 pounds.
他有着完美的职业生涯记录 33场比赛...
He has a perfect professional record, consisting of 33 bouts...
...33 胜 有 30 击倒获胜
...33 victories, including 30 knockouts.
原籍佛罗里达的坦帕...
Originally from Tampa, Florida...
...但代表了内华达的拉斯维加斯...
...but now fighting out of Las Vegas, Nevada...
...本界的无可置疑的 不可击败的...
...the reigning undisputed, undefeated...
...世界重量级冠军...
...heavyweight champion of the world...
...梅森·"分界线"...
...Mason "The Line"...
...迪克逊!
...Dixon!
好了 先生们
All right, gentlemen.
现在 梅森 洛奇 比赛前再讲下规则
All right, Mason, Rocky. We went over the rules in the dressing room.
这是个公平干净的比赛 小心 肾部拳 打后脑勺...
I expect a good, clean fight. Watch the kidney punches, rabbit punches...
...打下盘 当心 表现出运动员的职业精神
...low blows, be careful with those. Give me good sportsmanlike conduct.
记住 先生们 我很公平 但我很严格 握手!
Remember, gentlemen, I'm fair but I'm firm. Touch them up!
- 比赛愉快 - 冠军状态不是最好...
- Enjoy the ride. - The champ is not in the best shape...
...我们拭目以待吧 也许他想快点结束回家吧
...we've seen him in. Maybe he plans to phone this in and go home early.
- 这也不会令人惊奇 - 真高兴你来陪我了
- That wouldn't be a surprise. - Glad you could make it.
有一件事我们确定的关于洛奇的:
One thing about Rocky we know for sure:
看起来状态不错
This guy's showing up in shape.
- 老家伙疯了 - 他将要疯了 他在这儿
- The old man's crazy. - He's gotta be crazy. He's in here.
- 好的 - 放松 就是个表演赛
- Okay. - Take it easy. This is an exhibition.
行吗? 找他去吧
All right? Do it to him.
你有3局来设定节奏 每次你打到他 都要对他造成影响
You got three rounds to set a pace. Every time you hit him, make a dent.
- 知道了 - 洛奇·巴尔博亚比赛前...
- Got it. - The moments before...
...的时刻? 我真不敢相信就在这儿!
...a Rocky Balboa fight? I can't believe it's here!
第1局开始
Round one begins.
如果老乔治·弗尔曼用一拳震惊了世界...
If old George Foreman shocked the world with one punch...
...老洛奇·巴尔博亚为什么不能?
...why can't old Rocky Balboa?
竞技场上既有刺激...
And as much excitement as there is in the arena...
...令人感到不祥的预感
...there's a sense of foreboding as well.
现在 梅森·"分界线"·迪克逊 开始了他的拿手痛戳 就仿佛...
And now, Mason "The Line" Dixon goes to work with his jab as though...
...他在与世界一级的挑战者比赛
...he's fighting against the number one challenger in the heavyweight division.
看 这比预期的早了
See, this is to be expected early on.
你知道冠军会用他的痛戳保持距离...
You knew the champ would control the distance with his jab...
...他的高度 他的击打范围
...his height, his range.
巴尔博亚找机会打了一拳 太歪了
Balboa looking to get in a shot, misses wildly.
你喜欢这吗?
Did you like that?
看起来是速度袋与普通沙袋的比赛
It looks like a speed bag against a punching bag.
洛奇的击空很好理解...
Rocky's understandably frustrated...
...他退休了又来参加比赛
...but he came out of retirement to get into a fight.
象洛奇这样的人不喜欢被人当做玩具耍
Guys named Rocky don't like to be toyed with.
一拳仍可以扭转比赛
One punch could still turn it around.
显然他已经忘记了吃今早关节炎药了
Apparently he forgot his arthritis meds this morning.
洛奇又没打着
Rocky misses.
一颗由冠军发射的肉追踪导弹打中了下颚
There's a meat-seeking missile on the point of the chin by the champ.
- 迪克逊的更精确的痛戳 - 洛奇!洛奇! 洛奇!
- More pinpoint jabs by Dixon. - Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
一个巴尔博亚的右重拳 又一个左拳 又一个右拳!
And there's a hard right hand and a left and a right by Balboa!
他用一组合拳把迪克逊打到了边上!
He drives Dixon into the ropes with a series of shots!
人群沸腾了!
And the crowd goes berserk!
迪克逊惩罚了巴尔博亚刚才的重拳
Dixon punishing Balboa for the temerity of landing those shots.
这是在角落的进入实战的距离 巴尔博亚和迪克逊就这么打着
It's toe to toe in the corner. Balboa and Dixon letting it all go.
巴尔博亚实施了对冠军头部的有效打击
Balboa landing potent combinations to the head of the champion.
对迪克逊的唤醒召唤
A wake-up call for Dixon.
- 你怎么样? - 恩 我还不错
- You all right? - Yeah, I'm all right.
- 这家伙手套象是有砖头 - 你地下室的东西那?
- The man's got bricks in his gloves. - Where's the stuff in the basement?
- 还在 - 让他去战斗 好吗?
- It's still there. - He came to battle, okay?
- 试着把我打倒 - 听者  听我说
- Trying to knock me out. - Listen.
假如有一块骨头他能打断 他就会去打断
If there's a bone he can break, he's gonna do it.
- 对他表示尊重 - 那谁来尊重我?
- Give the man respect. - What about my respect?
CompuBox电脑数字显示了个令人毛骨悚然的记录
CompuBox numbers tell the grisly story here.
巴尔博亚在那轮实施13次打击9中
Balboa landed nine of 13 punches in that round.
迪克逊有令人难以置信的69中59
Dixon landed an incredible 59 out of 69.
- 为什么你不听我说? - 洛奇到过这儿上百万次了
- Why don't you listen to me? - Rocky's been here a million times.
在上一局被打后 他又迎来了新的一局
Coming out to start a round after he took a beating in the previous one.
- 记住我说的 好吗? - 我警告他了 我警告他了
- Remember what I said, okay? - I warned him. I warned him.
他累了 他的腿很快 或已经不听使唤了
He's tired. His legs are going fast, or already gone.
洛奇还能受的了真是难以置信
And what's truly extraordinary is that Rocky can still take it.
批准了执照的拳击委员会...
The boxing commission, which was criticized for licensing him...
...没准儿会被屠杀 假如洛奇发生了什么
...would be massacred if something happened to Rocky.
一个恐怖的左直拳! 洛奇摔倒了!
And a monstrous straight left hand! Down goes Rocky!
这大概就是比赛的结束了!
And that could conceivably be the end of the fight!
这大概就是表演赛了 但是 不 巴尔博亚站起来了
That could be the exhibition right there. But no. Balboa up.
裁判乔·科特斯问他是否要继续 洛奇说是的
Referee Joe Cortez asks if he wants to continue, and Rocky says yes.
就算是洛奇·巴尔博亚 这也太'勇敢了'吧
Even Rocky Balboa could be too brave for his own good.
迪克逊过来试着结束比赛 巴尔博亚差点摔倒!
Dixon comes right back to try to finish it. Balboa almost went down!
洛奇竟然把迪克逊向后推
Rocky actually shoves Dixon back.
迪克逊实施了野兽般的打击
As Dixon lands these brutal shots.
- 防住! 防住! - 近距离的无顾忌打击
- Cover up! Cover up! - Open shots at close range.
右  左 巴尔博亚倒下了!
Right and left hands, and down goes Balboa!
也许是他职业生涯的最后一次了!
Perhaps for the last time in his fighting career!
- 确实该是了 - 3! 4!
- That should do it. - Three! Four!
5! 6!
Five! Six!
- 起来! 起来! - 7!
- Get up! Get up! - Seven!
8! 9!
Eight! Nine!
- 你感觉怎么样 兄弟? 你还好吧? - 洛奇极其兴奋
- How do you feel, man? You okay? - Now Rocky is furious with himself.
他告诉科特斯他想继续比赛
He convinces Cortez he wants to keep fighting.
迪克逊告诉裁判结束了
Dixon's pointing at the ref to end it.
洛奇挥着手说他没事
Rocky waving his arms and saying he's fine.
- 他想继续! - 打啊! 打啊!
- He wants to go on! - Let it go! Let it go!
巴尔博亚回来了! 一个左拳 一个右拳...
And Balboa comes back! With a left and a right...
...第2次逼迪克逊到绳子边!
...and bulls Dixon into the ropes for the second round in a row!
迪克逊用野兽般的左直拳还击
Back comes Dixon with brutal left-hand shots.
- 迪克逊伤了他的手! - 追上他!
- Dixon hurt his hand there! - Go after him!
这是洛奇的最好机会!
This is Rocky's best chance!
冠军打洛奇的屁股时明显伤了手!
The champ obviously hurt his hand on Rocky's hip!
巴尔博亚立刻对他进行了攻击! 强大的右勾拳!
And Balboa immediately going to work to the body! Huge right hook!
巴尔博亚对的迪克逊身体进行猛烈的进攻! 都是重拳
Balboa ripping away at Dixon's body! These are big punches.
洛奇! 洛奇! 洛奇!
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
好的!
Yes!
洛奇·巴尔博亚打倒了当今的重量级拳王!
Rocky Balboa has knocked the reigning heavyweight champion down!
- 你打伤他了! - 梅森·"分界线"·迪克逊...
- You hurt him! - Mason "The Line" Dixon...
...从没收到过这么多的还击...
...has never taken this kind of punishment...
...在他的整个职业生涯!
...in his entire professional career!
大概他在使自己清醒 但那些重拳真的打倒了肋骨上了
Maybe he's clearing his head, but the body shots really caved in his ribs.
巴尔博亚在想击倒他!
Balboa is thinking knockout himself!
巴尔博亚另一个反击勾拳 又两个!
Another counterhook by Balboa, followed by two more!
迪克逊用自己的勾拳反击! 现在洛奇晕了
Dixon fires back his own hooks! Now Rocky's stunned.
一直在绳边打...
It's an all-out war along the ropes...
...第2局快完了 在场中巨大的混乱!
...as round two comes to a close amid a giant tumult in the ring!
难以置信
Incredible.
太好了!
All right!
欢迎来到洛奇的地盘
Welcome to Rockyland.
- 手怎么样? - 我的手断了
- How's the hand? - My hand's broken.
我们败了 那就怪你! 你!
We lose, it's your ass! Your ass!
几秒后就会失去知觉
It will numb up on you in a few rounds.
一旦开始麻木了 迪克逊就会有很难用拳
Once that hand numbs up, Dixon will be able to throw it hard.
那时 洛奇机会就到了
Until then, here is Rocky's chance.
- 别转身! - 忍住疼 冠军
- No reverse! - Take the pain, champ.
坚持住! 每个人都认为是个笑话 包括我!
Stay on him! Everybody thought this was a joke, including me!
现在没有人笑你了! 坚持住! 去扁他!
Now nobody's laughing! Stay on him! You go get him!
用力揍他!
Go out strong!
让他离你远些!
Keep him off you!
就那样! 就那样!
That's it! That's it!
你那局赢了 打垮他
You won that round. Break him down.
炸他! 炸他!
Bomb him! Bomb him!
太好了!
Yeah!
不停向他们扔炸弹!
Just keep throwing them bombs!
加油
Come on.
你能行的
You can do this.
洛克 洛克
Rocko. Rocko.
加油 上!
Yeah, come on, go!
越过他! 压扁他!
Go through him! Run over him!
在他身上发泄!
Unload on him!
下面 梅森!
Get down, Mason!
他们都用尽全力 兄弟们
They're leaving nothing on the table, guys.
观众还站着 大概下周他们也不会坐下了
The fans are still standing. They may not be able to sit down for a week.
- 他做得太伟大了! - 我做得比我想像得要好
- You're doing great! - I'm doing better than I thought.
- 你确定他没事? - 更坏得我都受过
- You sure he's okay? - I've had worse.
近距离对战 还有一局 谁能相信这是真的?
Toe to toe, one round to go. Who would've believed this was possible?
- 你还能看见吗? - 让我跟他说
- Can you see out of that eye? - Let me talk to him.
别花太大的力气了
Don't take any more chances than you have to.
没什么可证明的了 爸 没什么可证明的了
There's nothing more to prove, Pop. There's nothing more to prove.
我必须走完我要走的路
I gotta go out the way I gotta go out.
你能行的 洛克!
You can do it, Rocko!
- 还有1局 我们回家 - 好的 那就做吧
- One more round, we go home. - Okay, then do it.
有句老话说每个伟大冠军...
There's an old saying that every great champion has...
...都有场精彩的比赛 而洛奇 正在带来他的
...one great fight left in him, and Rocky is proving it so far.
- 来 握个手 - 洛克! 你人生中最后一场比赛!
- Come on. Touch them up. - Rocko! The last round of your life!
- 来, - 最后1局!
- Come on, guys. - The last round!
来 握个手 来 握个手
Come on. Touch them up, let's go. Touch them up.
- 你是个疯狂的老人 - 你会体验到的
- You are one crazy old man. - You'll get there.
我们来
Let's go.
10制的第10局 谁能想到...
Tenth round of a scheduled 10. Who would ever have dreamed...
...洛奇·巴尔博亚还在"表演赛"与...
...that Rocky Balboa would still be in this quote, "exhibition," against...
- ...重量级冠军? - 你能行的!加油!
- ...the heavyweight champion? - You can do it! Come on!
这场比赛好像是在给迪克逊上勇气的职业培训课
This fight is as though Dixon got on-the-job training in courage.
- 防住! 防住! - 他们都感觉不到疼了!
- Cover up! Cover up! - They're both in a pain-free zone!
这俩家伙在另一维比赛!
These guys are fighting in another dimension right now!
超越信念! 巴尔博亚照直冲向了迪克逊的拳
Beyond belief! Balboa just walking straight into Dixon's punches.
迪克逊的击打目标练习
Target practice for Dixon.
他们在交换右勾拳! 巴尔博亚抖了!
They're exchanging right hooks! Balboa's drilled!
迪克逊的拳来了! 他因为打他已经筋疲力尽了!
Here comes Dixon! He's exhausted from just punching the man!
把这孙子打倒 小梅!
Knock this bum out, Mase!
你对你孩子说得是什么? 不是你能打得多狠
What is it you said to the kid? It ain't about how hard you hit.
而是你能承受得了重击 然后一直向前
It's about how hard you can get hit and keep moving forward.
你能承受 一直向前
How much you can take and keep moving forward.
- 洛奇! 洛奇! 洛奇! - 起来
- Rocky! Rocky! Rocky! - Get up.
- 加油! 起来! - 洛奇! 洛奇! 洛奇!
- Let's go! Get up! - Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
洛奇!洛奇! 洛奇!
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
起来
Get up.
又一个猛兽般得重击 洛奇的老祖宗都能感受到这拳
Another monster body shot. Rocky's ancestors must have felt that one.
加油 洛奇! 用自己的手!
Come on, Rocky! Start moving those hands!
不到2分钟了
Less than two minutes to go.
人群都很惊讶巴尔博亚能起来
The crowd is astonished that Balboa got up.
- 加油! - 打他! 一条龙的!
- Come on! - Turn it over! All the way through!
报复十分疯狂!
And retaliates with fury!
打扁他!
Chop him down!
加油 洛奇! 加油!
Come on, Rocky! Come on!
收拾他现在!
Take him out now!
他们又开始对拳了!
They're trading shots again!
巴尔博亚不分什么的乱打!
Balboa is trying to hit anything and anywhere!
赢! 赢!
Win it! Win it!
太好了!
Yes!
你是个伟大的冠军 挺伟大的
You're a great champion. You got heart.
谢谢这次机会 好人
Thanks for the opportunity. Good man.
这真难以置信 这是我见过最伟大的事
That was unbelievable. That was the greatest thing I've ever seen.
你成功了 这就是你一直说的比赛
You did it. That's the kind of fighting you're talking about.
保利
Hey, Paulie.
野兽走了 野兽出去了
That beast is gone now. The beast is out.
体育中被用的最为过度的就是 伙计们 是"难以置信"
One of the most overused words in sports, guys, is "incredible."
我讨厌这么说 这真是难以置信
I hate to say it. This is incredible.
我们走!
Let's go!
女士们 先生们 在我们看记分牌前...
Ladies and gentlemen, before we go to the scorecards...
...让我们为俩位勇士欢呼吧!
...a round of applause for these two heavyweight warriors!
我们有个分歧判定
We have a split decision.
本·科劳斯 给95-94...
Adelaide Byrd scores it 95-94...
...迪克逊赢
...Dixon.
乔可·杰伯 给 95-94...
Chuck Giampa has it 95-94...
..巴尔博亚赢
...Balboa.
比尔·可汉姆 给 95-94...
And Bill Graham scores it 95-94...
...分歧判定的胜者 仍然是难以致胜的...
...for the winner by split decision, and still undefeated...
...世界重量级冠军...
...the heavyweight champion of the world...
...梅森·"分界线"·迪克逊!
...Mason "The Line" Dixon!
洛奇! 洛奇! 洛奇!
Rocky! Rocky! Rocky!
你知道 没有你我什么也干不了
You know, I couldn't have done nothing without you.
艾德里安 我们成功了
Yo, Adrian, we did it.
我们成功了
We did it.